Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Hey, Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Heat. Hey, Heat.
get
everybody hey
give me back.
Good morning and welcome to GitHub
Copilot Day. We are live here from the
studios at Microsoft and we have an
exciting day for you today. Thank you so
much for being with us. We know that
you're here from all around the world.
It's all hours of the day, maybe even
the middle of the night. We appreciate
that. Thank you so much. Today is all
about everything that's new in GitHub
Copilot. So much has been added, things
we're going to show you, not just today,
but things that have been added in the
past few weeks. And if you if you think
you've seen GitHub Copilot before, trust
me, you haven't seen it. So, we're
excited to be able to show you that
today. We have an exciting agenda. We
got two hours of live sessions followed
by two hours of live coding where myself
and Pierce are going to get together and
uh do a little coding live for a couple
of hours. Uh but we've got a lot of
stuff throughout the day including some
very special guests, but you'll have to
stick around and uh see who those folks
are. Uh but uh that'll be a surprise for
you. So again, we're glad you're here.
Um that's what we've got planned for you
today. It's going to be super exciting.
We're so glad that you're here with us.
And to get all of this started though,
I'd like to kick it over to Kyle C chief
operating officer at GitHub. And by the
way, uh GitHub representative on
Twitter. If you're there, make sure that
you reach out to him. He'd love to hear
from you. But let's kick it over to him
uh to get this whole thing started. And
let's do it. Excited. Let's go.
Hey everyone, I'm Kyle Dagel, the COO of
GitHub and the CMO of developer for
Microsoft. Welcome to our first ever
GitHub co-pilot day. We created this
event because honestly, we couldn't wait
until GitHub Universe next month to show
you all that we've been building. And
while we don't just want to announce
what's new and shiny, today we're going
to put it to work and show you what's
possible and hopefully give you a few
ideas to try yourself. So, if Copilot is
already a part of your daily workflow,
thank you for building with us. We think
you'll see a few surprises today. And if
you're new to Copilot, or honestly, if
you just haven't used it in a while,
this is a great day to take another look
and join us with the best version of
GitHub Copilot yet. If you're at this
event, you already know software
development is moving and changing
incredibly fast. Since April, monthly
commits on GitHub have more than doubled
from 1.4 billion commits to 2.9 billion
commits a month. That's a lot more code.
But more code alone isn't the goal. As
agents take on more of the loop, the way
we build shifts dramatically. A prompt
becomes parallel work. A single agent
becomes a coordinated system. And our
time shifts from producing every line to
shaping what gets built. That makes
quality, security, trust, and cost more
important, not less. Meeting that bar
takes more than a powerful model. It
takes the right system around it.
Context, tools, checks, and a smart way
to put every single model to work. And
that last part is much harder than it
sounds. A new model launches every week
just about, and they've become a part of
developer culture. We try them, we
compare notes, and we debate our
favorites. I do it, too. I did it all
weekend. Then the practical questions
arrive. Which model should I use for
this? For which task? At what cost? And
our time isn't unlimited and neither are
our tokens. That's why this past week we
announced hydrofusion in research
preview. A new approach designed to take
on those decisions for you. The idea is
simple, even if the engineering around
it isn't. Hydrofusion looks at the task
and decides whether to use one model
directly. Start with an efficient model
and escalate if needed or have one model
draft while another critiques and
improves the result. In offline evals
with terminal bench 2.1 Hydrofusion
improved quality by 4.9 points while
reducing estimated cost by 67% when
compared to Opus 5. You've heard us talk
a lot about our commitment to model
choice over the years and Hydrofusion is
the next evolution of that. better
quality, lower cost, and a lot less
model shopping for you to do. Now, it's
a research preview, so we're still
learning, but the direction is clear.
Better results shouldn't require more
complexity or cost more for developers.
Now, model orchestration is just one
piece of the system. The shared runtime
now powers the Copilot CLI and the
GitHub Copilot app. the Copilot SDK,
that same runtime becomes a foundation
for the tools and workflows that you
build. And you can start with the agent
infrastructure we use ourselves at
GitHub, then shape it around your users
and code bases and of course your way of
working. And while agents can do more of
the work, you still decide what ships.
Now, I know you came to see what this
changes in your workflow. So, let's get
right into it. We'll show Hydro Fusion
routing real tasks, agent skills, making
proven approaches reusable, and the
GitHub copilot app coordinating across
real repositories. Then we'll show how
you can build on the same foundation
with the C-pilot SDK. I also know many
of you came to watch Burke and Pierce
code live. I did too. and everything
before that will give them more powerful
tools to build with and more interesting
ways to code live with all of you. So,
everybody wins. Look, your workflow has
changed and GitHub Copilot has changed a
lot, too. I'm so excited for you to see
what we've been building. We've got a
lot to cover today. So, let's go build
>> I love that guy.
>> He's awesome. I love Kyle.
>> Classic Kyle. Classic Kyle.
>> Got to love him. I love those those
little dimples. It makes brings a smile
to my face just watching him talk. I
love it. I'm James Montag with me.
Pierce Boen over here.
>> Hello.
>> And we're super jazzed just to be
bringing you everything that Kyle just
talked about. So, let's just honestly
get right into it. Everything that
Kyle's been talking about is how GitHub,
GitHub Copilot, the amazing tools from
Microsoft and our amazing partners are
really help building an agentnative
engineering system. Right. From idea to
production to security to deployment and
so much more in that entire iterative
loop. Every single day, Piers, I am
changing how I build software. What's
unique is we used to wake up and say,
"What bug am I going to start working
on? What feature am I going to get 25%
done today?" I wake up every day now and
I say, "How many bugs am I going to fix?
How many features am I going to add? How
much value do I get to add to my
software for my customers?" That's
really amazing.
>> Yeah, our our jobs have fundamentally
changed a lot in the last year,
especially since the advent of agents,
definitely since the beginning of AI.
And it's awesome that, you know, not
only can I use something like GitHub
Copilot to do these things faster, but I
have that entire end to end where I can
start with an issue, I can complete, you
know, fixing that bug with GitHub
Copilot, I can deliver that software all
with the same platform. Like pretty
amazing that that's all in one.
>> And like honestly, GitHub Copilot is
everywhere, right? everything that Kyle
talked about from the app to the CLI to
the SDK enabling you to build your own
agents leveraging the GitHub copilot
agent harness but the deep integrations
VS VS Code teams slack that we're going
to talk about and our amazing
integrations into Xcode Intelligj neovim
and integrations with raycast and so
many more places where you can use your
copilot subscription and what's crazy is
that these are all iterating and moving
so fast and honestly the team has been
cooking if my slides will progress.
Let's see. Uh oh,
we threw these slides earlier, right?
Oh.
>> Oh, there we go.
>> Oh, when PowerPoint goes. Okay,
PowerPoint.
Okay, let's go ahead and open this up.
Oh, there we go. Nice little driver
issue. Perfect. We're good. Coming back.
We'll switch back to us really quick.
Perfect. All right. And I'm right back
into my slide deck. Let me go ahead and
go into here. All right. And we're back
because the team has been cooking.
>> We have been.
>> There we go. And shipping so many new
features, uh, new models, enhancements,
performance, everything every single
day. Basically, when you wake up, brand
new updates, ready to integrate,
ready to cook.
>> Yeah, we're moving super fast. Like,
it's not just like hypothetical that AI
is making us move faster. I see that
every day on our product and engineering
teams across all of our products that
James just said. I know it's a lot to
keep up with. And so we have the GitHub
change log where you can follow all the
latest news. So just keep an eye on that
for what the team's been shipping.
>> And let's get in the code and let's
cook.
>> Let's do it.
>> Okay. So I'm going to start over here uh
directly in a place that maybe some of
us are every single day either in Teams
or Slack, some sort of channel. And
actually I'm going to open this up. A
little scary, but here I am inside of
>> nothing like sharing your actual Slack
in a live stream.
>> It's real. Uh, so you, me, and Burke
have been working on a little app we
call three up, so we can kind of stay
connected with each other.
>> And this is the GitHub co-pilot
integration directly into Slack. And it
looks like uh Burke's been switching up
uh last night some new layouts here. I
can take a look at what he's got cooking
here. That looks really nice. It's a way
for us to stay connected basically
throughout the day. And we can see
directly inside of there, we have these
code channels. So you can add and
connect your GitHub repository directly
to it. Here it is, the three-up
repository. It's on a branch. It has a
PR already open. Uh, and it right here
is using soul. Um, and if I tap over
here on the artifacts, I can actually
see a live preview of the running
application. So, I can see that you and
I have been committing some code and
Burke
>> classic doing. So, we can do our
check-ins, everything like that. Now,
this is live. So, I can say, hey, we
forgot to add Wes uh boss. add him and
call it forup. Uh, and his GitHub is Wes
Boss. He's gonna be with us coding live
later today.
>> How could we forget Wes?
>> You can't forget Wes. So, now what's
going to happen here is that the agent
is going to start to pick up the
conversation that's in the loop.
>> And in fact, if I go over uh to my
agent, we can actually see the exact
agent session in real time, behind the
scenes, if you will. Yep.
>> So, we can see all those messages that
Burke was posting directly here. We can
see all the different calls that were
going on along the way right there.
Okay, we got some live mics possibly.
So, we'll see. So, this will start to
cook and then it'll start to update our
live preview, which is super awesome.
>> Yeah. And I the thing I love about this
integration is, you know, GitHub
Copilot's coming in. You said it's where
you work and for a lot of us like our
collaboration tools, whether it's Slack
or Teams, right? That is where we're
having a lot of conversations. On the
GitHub copilot app team, we have a
channel. people just pop in and be like,
"Hey, I love this in the app. Yeah, I'm
I'm struggling with this. This is
confusing. I have this bug." And like,
you know, pre-Slack integration, we
would copy pasta, write that into the
copilot app, VS Code, something like
that.
>> Now, immediately inside of Slack, where
all that context is, they've already
uploaded the log, some screenshots, a
video. I just say, "Act GitHub,
>> can you go investigate this?
>> Propose a fix."
>> There you go. And then it'll kick right
in and it'll be good to go.
>> Yep.
>> All right. Now, let's go over and
actually focus on one of the things that
we've been and the team's been working
really hard on is the GitHub copilot
app. Yep.
>> It's your hub for all things code really
and all things copilot and all things
GitHub.
>> Yep.
>> So, we actually start right here on the
new tab. What do you want to build
today?
>> So, I figured I just kind of walk
through a little bit here because
there's a lot of different options here.
First, you see on the lefth hand side,
new work, automations, customizations,
we'll get to it. and all my projects.
These can be local folders, remote Git
repositories, projects on GitHub,
anything you want. So, I have been
working on a bunch of things here and
I'll actually show some of the active
sessions I have going on. So, here I'm
able to go in and pick what mode I want.
Interactive, plan, autopilot mode, and I
have tool permission calls. You're in
control. You can always ask, you can
approve all. And there's the brand new
assisted which is experimental but
basically it automatically approves tool
requests that pass an LLM safety check.
So like if you want to do like a mpm
lint like that's probably going to be
pretty safe. You're good to go. It'll
handle it for you.
>> Also I want to call out there's a brand
new just launched today new auto
optimizations. So before you have auto
mode which based on your prompt will
pick a model for you at a nice little
discount. You can now optimize it for
your request. You can give it a little
hint. So you can do it for efficiency,
balanced or you can do intelligent and
it'll pick different models based on
your needs. Now of course we have all
sorts of models right? So here we have
all the different models from anthropic
openai MAI Gemini XAI and I've even
connected my open router to actually get
access to different Quen models too. I
could even run them with O Lama or
Foundry Local on my machine. You can see
I got all sorts of models all the models
right. So I'm actually going to for this
one let's do uh Luna and I'm going to
put it on extra high. You're in control
of reasoning, context window, your
accessibility. Now, I want to build a
brand new application from scratch. So,
let's see if we can cook. I'm here in my
Seattle Day Planner, and Pierce is
always visiting me in the Pacific
Northwest, and I want to optimize and
build a beautiful website for the
greatest day. So, I'm going to hit this
little dictate button so I can actually
go ahead and talk to it. Hey, okay, I
want to build out a beautiful website
and uh I want it to be for my friends
that visit Seattle, Washington, and I
want to be a day planner for them. And
specifically, I want it to be for all
the best coffee shops and awesome
attractions, you know, like the Space
Needle, Car's Park, and uh Pikes Place,
for example. And what I really want it
to be is a really visually rich, in
fact, I've given you a folder here
called assets. So, take a look at the
photos there and use those. But make it
so they can really kind of plan out
their single day, show it on a map, and
then what I want you to do is after you
get that built, go ahead. There's no
GitHub repository. So create the GitHub
repository, push all the code up, and
then go ahead and configure GitHub pages
for me and deploy it automatically for
me with a CI/CD pipeline. Thank you.
And I'm just going to go ahead and fire
it off.
>> Perfect.
>> Now you got an idea in your brain. You
just tell it from idea to production.
Now this is going to start cooking. Now,
a few things are going to happen here.
This is going to take a look at my
skills, my MCP servers, anything like
that, and start to get to work. So, we
can see uh it's renamed my session. It's
moved it into my Seattle planner folder
here. I have some things available to me
like VS Code, the run. I can take a look
here and it's going to think it through
it. It's loading impeccable, which is a
skill that we have. We'll talk about in
a bit. And it's going to get to work.
>> Awesome.
>> That's going to take some time, Pierce.
So, let's let's keep moving on because
that's what this is about, right? You
got to keep moving as this is going. So
the thing that I want to show off next
is actually some automations that I run.
>> Okay,
>> so here is really cool and this is kind
of a nice little hidden feature here is
and by hidden feature I mean it's
directly right there for you. Uh is that
these are all my automations for my
personal work but also for my code. So I
have some things here like doing a daily
issue triage for my application uh tiny
clips that reviews all my GitHub issues,
looks at priorities and enriches the
issues. Um, here I have an accessibility
audit and every week I run cost tips
using Chronicle because I want to make
sure that I'm being costefficient. I
also have um one that's connected to
work IQ. So, it looks at all of my teams
and emails and gives me a daily report.
So, I can go ahead and kick it off and I
can look at all my runs. I was shutting
down the apps. I stopped them abruptly,
but I can see all the ones that were
running here. And you can get
inspiration from the templates. They're
all right here. So, you can click on
one, get it set up. And I'm just going
to go ahead and do a new one here. And
I'm gonna call this uh this is a a
prompt about removing dead code that
Burke gave me. I call it dead code.
>> Burke's taking a lot of strays today.
>> He was like a lot of dead code. So here
I'm just going to say dead code. Verify
everything. Look for obsolete f flags.
Open a PR. And I'm going to go ahead and
do this on this pickle ball app I've
been creating for the .NET Conf keynote.
And here I could just auto say auto. You
have all the options. And I'm just going
to run it in the cloud.
>> Perfect.
>> And I can say all tools. I have full
control. anything I want and I can go
ahead and just fire that off and select
it here. So, there's the kitchen sync.
Create it. Boom. And now that's going to
run every single week in the cloud and
get a report and the PR is going to be
generated automatically.
>> Yeah. Uh automations are super cool. I,
you know, like you said, we see a lot of
people building personal automations for
toil in their day. Uh I have some that
like run telemetry queries and do things
like that. Help me prepare for my day.
Um triage feedback we have on the repo
from social media. tell me like what's
important, but also we're seeing a lot
of engineering teams doing things like
issue triage, auto investigation, things
like that with these automations. So,
it's super cool to see what people are
doing with them.
>> And we can see that the Seattle planner
is asking me some questions and it's
because I forgot to put it in autopilot
mode. So, let's go ahead and switch it.
And now it's just going to keep going,
but it did ask me questions because it
was in that interactive mode. It wanted
to understand a little bit more. So, I'm
going to go ahead and let it cook here a
little bit more. And I'm going to get to
other work. So, if you click on my work,
these are all of the projects that I
have here. So these are all of my uh
issues, PRs that are open, closed. I can
look at pull requests, reviews. I can
create a custom dashboard with any
filter I want, which is really nifty. I
use this active one all the time because
if I just go to GitHub, I have 550
repos. It's a little bit much. So I can
create my filters and I can look at my
work here and I can see anything
assigned to me specifically. So, for
example, if I wanted to get to work on
this uh big feature request that a lot
of my uh users of my stream timer, which
I use for countdown clocks, um here it
only does a system beep. I want to have
custom like MP3s and waves. Uh if I want
to create a new session, I have it here.
Start a new session. I'm going to do it
on this machine and just
>> perfect
>> starts it up. It's going to
automatically attach this issue and I
can say issue fix and go. It
automatically creates the work tree for
me. So I don't have to worry about
conflicts automatically or anything like
that with my any branches from main.
It's going to pull everything local and
then it's going to get to work. And just
like that, I'm already starting to do
multi- aent processing across multiple
projects, which is super cool.
>> Yeah, it's great. And I love having the
native like GitHub collaboration built
in where I not only have my agents
working but also all my planned work. I
feel like now with agents like the
temptation is like it's it's not it's
very easy to start things but it's
actually very difficult to discern what
should I be doing right and so having
that super close to where my agents are
working has been super helpful for me.
>> Totally. So let's go into one that I've
been doing earlier. Here I have an
application called Tiny Clips which
allows me to take screenshots on Mac and
Windows. And I've been working
specifically on multicapture editing
because when I would take a a screenshot
and if I did another one, it would close
the old one. So I wanted multiple. So I
was working here. I kind of did
something very similar. I basically came
up over here and I said, "Hey, here's an
issue. Let's trace through this and get
to work." And it put together a nice
little um proposal for me. I can see
everything here. Here's the plan. The
great part here is if I want to get
closer to the code, I can look at the
changes or I could just open it in VS
Code or my favorite code editor here. If
I bring up VS Code, we can see that I
have the same exact uh work tree down
here. So, here's that work tree. It
opens it automatically when you click
that button. I have the same exact
session. We can see it's running here in
the Copilot agent harness. I can see all
of the steps. I can chat back and forth
directly there. I can create the PR
here. It'll sync between the two. I can
click on it and get really deep into the
application, run it, do anything I want,
which is super nice. So, that deep tight
integration between your favorite
developer tools. Now, one thing that is
missing here though is my slashVS code
uh buddy. Oh, there he is.
>> Oh, there he is. Oh, hey, how's it
going? He's like, hey, what's going on?
Yeah. Oh, there you go. And you kind of
th him around just so we kind of have
like nice interactive elements in the G
co-pilot app. Justin and the team been
working on our VS Code pet, which
doesn't have a name yet. And we'll talk
about a little bit more here how you can
help name them too. I get achievements.
I got this little crown on. So the more
I'm using the agents and investigating
and learning new capabilities. It's all
there. But I want to point out right all
the same models. Everything's available
here for us. We have, you know,
different reasoning levels, the agent
modes, everything like that. Permission
checks, all the things that we kind of
just saw. So that nice agent harness
running across, which is rad. Now, if
I'm back over in the app, right, I've
reviewed the code. I'm good to go. I can
just oneclick create a PR. This is now
going to do a few things. It's going to
check any requirements I might have in
the repo. It's going to fire off right
here to go ahead and open that pull
request which runs a skill. And it will
then go ahead and fire that off and
start to run my CI and CD checks. Now,
that's going to take a second or so
because I'm building Windows and Mac
applications based on what I'm changing.
So, I did one earlier that for all
intents and purposes is exactly the same
and I created the PR ahead of time. Uh
so we can see that I basically did the
same exact thing for the multi-edits and
then I have the full validation here.
But I want to point out that I have the
GitHub copilot uh review agent running
on github.com. So when I fired this off,
it ran all my checks and everything
seemed to pass uh which was good, but it
left me a comment here on some code
improvements. So what's great with this
integration is that I can one-click fix
unresolved comments or what I like to do
is from this dropdown I can click ready
to merge and merge and see all the
checks but I can also turn on agent
merge and agent merge allows it the
agent to automatically address review
issues CI failures resolve conflicts and
a lot more. So when you're working on a
lot of different branches and a lot of
work trees, this becomes super nice and
you'll see agent merge is going to get
to work and it's going to start to merge
load the scale and get to work and
commit back that code automatically. Now
I did not do the automatically merge
pull request. But you could if you're
really in that really tight integration,
you feel good about it, you can go ahead
and put that out there.
>> Yeah. And I mean, even before AI, every
single team struggles with like, okay, I
did the work, I have the PR, now I have
to spend a week babysitting this three
thing through to actually getting
merged. That problem got worse with AI
because we're now sending more PRs than
ever thanks to things like the GitHub
core app. Um, and so agent merge is
awesome because now I can submit the PR,
I turn on agent merge, I don't have to
babysit the thing, and when all the
checks are addressed and I feel good
about the state of the PR, I can merge
it in.
>> Exactly. Now, let's get back up and look
at our hub. Let's see if it is how it's
going. Okay, looks like we have a
canvas. So, that's good. Let's go and
see here. We have our Seattle canvas.
Okay, this is looking pretty good. So,
we got a Seattle day planner. Uh, build
a day worth wandering. So, we can start
with a place. Beautiful. A good space
needle. We have a a beautiful map here
that we can outline our location. That's
really cool. They hand drew that. That's
amazing. Um, I can copy this route and I
have see all the different locations
here. So, I did provided the photos. Um,
but I actually worked earlier and I had
Copa go grab all the different photos
for him, which is cool. So, we can see
all the different places here and it
actually filtered and it's testing the
app in real time. So, it's actually been
adding.
>> So, this is actually a browser inside
the GitHub copilot app.
>> This is directly here and you can pick
and polish. You can pick elements and
you can see that it's been invoking
clicking elements, reading elements, and
doing a lot more. So, that built-in deep
integration directly inside the co-pilot
app. So now this is going to get to work
validating because it kind of waited a
few minutes for me to answer a question
and then it's going to create our repo.
So I figure while we wait there,
>> I want to also show you how I do a lot
of my iOS and Android development on my
Mac. So you have my Mac. So let's head
over to my Mac over here. And I know
we've been working on this weight
tracking application.
>> We have. Yes. Um you know we're we're
entering winter so it's time time to
bulk again. So maybe not the time for
weight loss, but that's okay. Um, we've
been building this iOS app together in
the GitHub copod app. And I think one
really cool thing like uh you know the
GitHub copod app can be used to build
any sort of thing, right? Uh we just saw
how we can build web apps. We have a
built-in browser. Um there's an
extensibility model called canvases
which we'll show later today uh inside
the GitHub copilot app. And here I
actually have a canvas for testing and
viewing the iOS simulator directly in
this app. So I can say with natural
language here's what I want in my app
right here inside the GitHub copilot
app. I can validate right here. Of
course this is like a real simulator. I
can interact with it. I can come over
here. I could change like the viewport
if I wanted to try a different sim
simulator. And it looks like from
scrolling up like this thing can
actually go and drive the actual app
from the agent. It can self- validate
like if I ask it to test things. And it
looks like we got to get this things
ready to ship. So we need some
screenshots for this app store. So I'm
just going to fire it off and I'll let
the app take care of that. Like I'm not
going to go manually capture these
screenshots myself. It's not 2025
anymore.
>> Exactly. This is a uh a canvas that
ships and it has an MCP server so it can
actually speak directly uh to it. So it
can understand what to do. So this is
great and you're in that iteration loop
just like we saw in the web that
specifically it was off testing it. And
we can see hands up, hands up, I'm not
doing anything,
>> right? Native native and this is a
native Swift application directly right
here. Yep. Uh, and you can see
everything it's doing, including asking
you questions and anything that you want
it to do.
>> Yep. Yeah. And I I mean, I think uh the
really cool thing about the GitHub
Copilot app is I feel like it allows me
to focus on the outcome that I'm trying
to achieve, right? What is the feature
I'm trying to build? Uh, imparting my
wisdom on architectural choices, things
like that. And I'm not super close to
the code, but that's kind of intentional
right here. And you can even do things
like agentic self-verification, which of
course is your firing off 10 things at
once. like the less things you actually
have to do in any one of these threads,
the more things you can do, right? And
of course, like you said, like if I ever
wanted to go and look at the code, I can
do so in VS Code. So maybe let's hop
over to VS Code actually.
>> Yeah. In fact, I was working on another
app, a net Maui application on Android,
this little financial application. Yep.
>> And I think what was great here is that
these same MCP servers, the same tools,
the same agent harness runs it here. So
we can see our custom Maui agent. And
the same thing, we have all of our
different devices. In this case, I'm
deploying it here on Android. And you
can run at the same exact prompt to have
it test everything. So no matter what
you're building, no matter what you want
to do, it can drive it. And I think
what's cool is like a lot of developers
using VS Code are used to like the
extensions, right? There's tons of
extensions. The mobile canvas is
extension from John Dick here at
Microsoft.
>> Um, and we can see that now the agent is
parsing, taking screenshots, navigating
fully through you, and it's going to
self- validate. So I recently added an
interest calculator. So, I wanted to
self validate it, take screenshots, add
it to documentation, and now it's just
going to kind of get to work doing its
thing automatically, scrolling around,
everything that we need it to do in real
time, which is super powerful. So,
implement something, figure it out, and
like it's so cool to watch it, do
>> it's literally taking screenshots and
stuff right now. It's super cool.
>> So, while that's cooking and doing some
screenshots, I think the thing that we
should really talk about is the
extensibility of the GitHub Copilot app.
>> That's right. So uh in the GitHub
copilot app, if you go to this customize
tab, uh you can go install MCP servers,
plugins, skills, canvases,
>> essentially any customization you want
inside the GitHub copilot app to make
the C-pilot app work just like you and
your team, right? So I can come in, I
can add MCP servers. So my team's using
Azure DevOps, I'm using Figma, I want to
do device testing with Playright, I can
install that right here. Of course,
plugins from marketplaces like awesome
copilot uh that our community has
curated. So I can, you know, oneclick
install things like work IQ to give the
GitHub copilot app context on my
Microsoft 365 documents, conversations,
team stuff, skills. Um we got Matt PCO
right after us. We got the grill me
skill. He's going to tell us all about
it. But uh you can go install and
discover skills from your your
marketplaces. You can even actually add
your own organizational marketplace. So
we have that at Microsoft. like we have
a curated set of plugins for just people
here at Microsoft. You can add that
market uh marketplace registry directly
to the GitHub copod app. So every single
engineer on your team has access to
those plugins. And of course canvases,
right? Uh canvases are basically a
visual way for you to drive the app. So
uh we saw the iOS simulator canvas, but
there's other canvases like Azure
DevOps, Foundry, Jira. We use the Sentry
canvas a lot on our team. It doesn't
just show us like active issues we have
for Century, but from that canvas, I can
actually go in and I can say, "Oh, this
is the top, you know, performance issue
we have in the GitHub copod app.
>> Fix fix this bug." It's literally one
click away. And so then my interaction
model shifts from just being so focused
on chat to now I have the canvas and I'm
using that to actually fire off agent
sessions in the app.
>> Let's head back to my PC uh because I
got two more things that I want to show.
Perfect. The first is that you can build
your own canvases. You can use
/createcanvas
and in fact I have my own I have my own
repo actions so I never have to leave
the copilot app to see all of my actions
running on github.com and for tiny clips
I actually created my entire release
dashboard here I can create release
notes generate PRs tag releases and see
everything all in real time including
what's live for Mac and on Windows and I
can even see the status of what's on
Windguet today and what's released which
is super cool so you can just build your
own and these can leverage the GitHub
copilot SDK to infuse use the agent
inside of these canvases which is super
duper cool. All right, I have two more
things I want to show. First is
something down here which is uh kind of
interesting called
>> is this WSL?
>> Is it WSL?
>> Yeah, I want to point out here there's
this little icon here and it says it's
running in WSLuntu and this is a brand
new feature. If you go under
environments, you'll see that I am
connected to the Windows subsystem for
Linux. So, I built a little application
that I can run here with this little um
uh run button. Uh supposed to be there.
Where is it at? See, run the app.
There we go.
It was there. It should run it. Let's
see. I think I need to There we go.
Perfect. And so, the GitHub Copilot app,
of course, I can run sessions locally on
my machine. Uh I can also run sessions
in the cloud. And now I can run them on
remotes like WSL as well.
>> And there it is. So there's my little
app. Is this WSL? It is. It is indeed
WSL right here. In fact, I'll prove it
to you really quick. I'm going to go
over to my terminal. I'm type in btop
over here. I'm going to make this
bigger. And now I have BTOP running
directly inside of it. So this is right
directly inside of inside of this. And
you can just run everything configured
inside of WSL. So you can configure all
those environments. Last thing really
quick, I'm going to head over to the CLI
over here. I want to talk about
hydrofusion. So the best model is not
having to pick a model at all. Uh so
here I've gone ahead and I've created a
new work tree with the SLworkree command
and I'm going to tell it to get to work
on this and hydrofusion here is going to
pick the best approach best on the
prompt has picked critique here and it's
going to do a few things. It's going to
do a first pass with a primary worker.
It's going to then understand that pass
and go back and critique it and it's
going to have a readonly reviewer to
provide notes on it and then it'll do a
revision pass and then go ahead and
implement it automatically. The cool
part here is all this is happening. You
can see my AI credits in real time go
and I've used less than one so far right
to do these first pass in primary. So
the team is working really hard on the
output but the idea is you shouldn't
have to worry about the output until the
end when it all sort of finishes which
is really nice. And there's going to be
a deep dive in hydrofusion. So I'm not
going to go too deep onto it. But I also
want to point out if I hit the left
arrow, I got a bunch of things cooking
over here, too. I'm a big gooey person.
So I love a tuy. And I love that I can
just click on things and I can navigate
around into all of my different sessions
here. So I can go and I can see here all
of my sessions. And I want to also point
out that all of these sessions that I've
been going on here, I've been using
Hydra Fusion on and they also show up
inside if I want to the GitHub copilot
app because they're all there. There's
an option to show your CLI sessions. So,
as these are working back and forth,
they're all readily available for you.
And then this is going to go ahead
finish this off. And if I wanted to
create a new session, I can just click
on new session. I can view all my issues
for the repo, open pull requests,
everything. Deep integration. I love
that I can click on things. I love a
good mouse click. All right, let's wrap
this thing up as Copilot continues to
work. Okay, first thing is you can get
the GitHub Copilot app today. gh.io/app
to turn your idea into reality and start
to check out all of these amazing
features that we've talked about today.
the rich ecosystem that continues to
build out. Publish your plugins, publish
your MCP servers and go ahead and
configure these for your team, your
project or your enterprise. We love to
see this continue to be built out. More
models are added every single day and
you have those readily available to you.
Or if you're like me, I'm auto mode and
now I'm hydrofusion all day, every day
as the default inside the CLI. I simply
love it. And of course, you can bring
your own key, configure anything you
want. Now I do want to talk here like
the hydrofusion part is really unique.
We saw it use critique but we can also
see that there's other modes such as a
single shot cascade and these different
are automatically selecting different
models at the right time for the task
and switching when it makes sense to
cache bust efficiently and effectively.
Deep dive into the blog post on
Hydrausion. Type in Hydrofusion GitHub
into your favorite search engine. Read
the deep dive blog post. It is awesome
to just see on what the team is working
on. We showed the deep integration into
Slack. Also available in Teams. If you
haven't gotten that configured, you got
to do it. It's mind-blowing to work on
stuff. A bunch of great things to help
you dream, build, and ship.
Last thing really, really quick that I
want to point out while you take a
screenshot really quick is that there's
tons of great stuff here. Matt's gonna
be right after us, grilling us hard with
his skills, deep dive on Hydro Fusion,
folks from the VS Code, the C-pilot
team, and you all be back live coding
with Wes, hopefully an updated website
um automatically there. But the fun
doesn't stop today. The community is
rallying behind the GitHub Copilot Dev
Days, and there's hundreds of events
around the globe. You can go to this URL
or scan that QR code to take you to the
Luma calendar where you'll see hundred
events. I'm doing one in Portland in
October. So, if you're in the Portland
area, hope to see you. Portland, Oregon,
not Maine. Uh, so hope to see you there.
And these are really awesome to see the
community come together. Also, I want to
point out that our little buddy does
need a name.
>> He does.
>> And we have a whole survey that the
team's been putting on for a chance to
win a whole month of GitHub Copilot Max
if the name is selected. Now, you can go
ahead and go to ak.ms/vscode-p,
the same command inside of VS Code. But
the team's been cooking up a little
trailer, so let's go ahead and play that
now.
All
right, that's going to do it for this,
but we have so much more in store. So,
as always, happy coding. Pierce, thanks
for being here. And over to you, Burke.
Hey, thank you so much, James and
Pierce. I love the VS Code pet. That
thing is awesome. Uh, send in your
names. Don't don't send in Bodie
McBoatface, okay? Someone's already sent
that in. Don't, please don't do that.
Now, that was amazing. Uh, there was so
many things in there, things that even I
didn't know existed. The mobile canvas
is awesome. It makes me want to build a
mobile app. So, uh, in the I need ideas,
though. So, please in the chat, give me
an idea for the next um, multi-billion
dollar mobile app so I can get right on
that. Now, when I do build apps, one of
the first things I do is use a skill
called Grill Me. And grill me is might
be one of the most popular skills out
there. Um, I'm sure a lot of you use it
and it's just where the AI asks you a
ton of questions to help you figure out
exactly what you want to build. And we
are excited to have the creator of that
skill and many others here today to talk
to us a little bit about skills. So
without further ado, it's the man who
literally has the solution for your
skill issues, Mr. Matt PCO.
Hello folks. Thank you so much for
having me. Um I've got a hot mic in my
ear by the way just for the production
team. Um so I'm extremely delighted to
be here and I've been somehow come into
possession of the most or the second
most popular skills repo in the world.
I'm coming to you from sunny Oxfordshire
right now and I'm going to introduce to
you you to the skills repo and also
maybe look at a couple of new things
that are coming to the skills repo and
how you can apply those in GitHub
copilot. So first of all let me show you
the repo. We are up to around 259k stars
which is fairly wild to me. I never
really thought we would get there and
the place we're going to start is in the
main flow here. So the idea of these
skills is you can really ship any size
of work that you want to. And the place
we pretty much always start is with this
grill with docs skill. For those who
haven't used my skills before, this is
essentially a way to align yourself with
the agent. And it means that like it's
so often that you will get the agent and
you will look at the work that they've
done and they will just have not
produced the thing that you want them
to. And so doing a kind of preession
grilling kind of before the agent does
any work whatsoever I found has been
absolutely essential. And this is what
that looks like in GitHub copilot. So,
if we head over to the terminal here, I
have been doing some actual real work on
my repo this morning. My repo is a
course video manager where I handle all
of my video editing. I manage all of my
course videos. And let's take a look at
what that actually looked like. So, what
I did first of all is I use GitHub
issues to coordinate all the things I
want to change about the repo itself.
This means that keeping those outside of
the repo, I just get a lot more value in
pumping those into uh automated loops,
in passing them directly to agents, and
sometimes even just triggering them via
labels. But that's kind of outside the
scope for today. But what that looks
like in GitHub Copilot is it means I can
just go into issues. I can press W here
to open up a work tree and I ended up
inside this work tree here. So this
little example, if I press enter to go
in, what happens is I just literally say
grill with docs issue 1612. And this
issue was one that I actually needed to
fix. It's basically adding something
into the CLI that comes served with this
uh course video manager. Now what
happened first is it goes and does an
exploration in a sub agent. Very nice.
And once it's done the exploration, once
it understands what it wants to grill me
about, then it begins asking its
questions. And so these questions here,
supported hierarchy selectors. So the
problem here is that I've got an entity
that I want to fetch called a beat. And
that beat is attached to videos, but it
wants to be able to search not only on
videos, but on lessons where there are
multiple videos and on sections where
there are multiple lessons beneath that.
And so it says, okay, both selectors
mutually exclusive. I'm going to um use
a dictation tool to just answer these
questions fully because I kind of
prepped a little bit for this. so I know
what I'm doing. Yeah, I think we should
use um all three supported hierarchy
selectors. I think using the
deterministic hierarchy order makes
sense. And then videos with an empty
plan, I think we can just exclude them.
I don't think we need to add any kind of
uh extra signal in there.
So now that's gone in. I'm just going to
press return there. And it's now going
to ask me the next round of questions.
In other words, what Grill with Docs is
doing is it's pushing out the frontier
of these questions and we're reaching
alignment slower and slower or rather
faster and faster and faster. So, it's
gone and kicked off another explore
agent and while it's kicking off the
explore agent, it's going to ask me some
more questions. This level of alignment
basically means that you and the agent
are reaching a shared understanding
together. You are figuring out where
you're going together. And this is
really useful in situations where you
have lots of unknown unknowns where you
don't quite know where you're going. And
so I absolutely love this. But then what
happens next? What do you do after
you've done a grilling session? Well,
let's take a look at what happened next.
So in my real version here, what I did,
this is fairly long chat history. We did
our grilling session. It did a bunch of
asked user bunch of questions. asked the
user more questions and then it kicked
off and actually implemented it. So what
grill we what grill with docs does is it
takes that set of questions that it
asked you and then tries to reach a
shared understanding with you and then
what we end up with is a nice little
pull request. So if I head into the PR
itself, I've done a little trick
actually in the PR which I'm rather
proud of and it's actually not my trick,
it's somebody else's. So if we take a
look at uh where was the PR here? It was
uh add
this one add bulk section and lesson
beat lists. Now this PR body probably
looks rather nice to you. What we have
is we have this rather nice little diff
showing exactly what has changed about
the CLI. You have just this very small
amount of preserves the current compact
uh excludes uh archive beats, lessons,
etc. And we have a nice little mermaid
diagram which we can open up here. So we
see that sections, okay, sections
contain lessons that have a fractional
order. Lessons contain videos and we can
access those with the lesson. And then
videos contain the beats with their
fractional order. You know, this is a
real application. There's stuff
relatively complex here. And we can dive
into this mermaid diagram and this diff
and understand it a lot better. And the
thing that's firing here, the thing
that's making this look nice is not my
skill. Actually, I'm going to shout out
Dexter Horthy at Human Layer Skills
who's written a brilliant skill called
Show Me. Helps the user understands the
current topic visually with concise
diagrams, code shaped sketches, and
focused HTML artifacts. I mean, just
look at this stuff.
This is basically a really really nice
set of tools for understanding how code
changes. we have a pseudo code. Um like
if you have changes to an algorithm
that's relatively complicated, we can
show it as pseudo code. We can show
runtime control flow as a call tree
here. This UI structure one is amazing
for front-end components because it
shows exactly where each component is.
It can sort of show stuff changing
across different components and
different files. And then we have
mermaid diagrams of course which GitHub
handles naturally. And we have file
responsibility and all that stuff. The
one I really like is diff. So using diff
for component changes, for file layout
changes, for call tree and call stack
changes. And what this skill does is it
really encourages the agent to push
towards using these uh sort of diff
views instead of writing a bunch of
stuff in text. And so the nice thing
about this PR is that it's really short
to read. You know, there's less than 100
words here. And once you've dived in to
understand the mermaid diagram, you dive
into understand the diff, it's pretty
nice. And so as part of the skill or
part of this session here, which is uh
back here, at some point in the session,
I said, okay, use show me to create the
PR. Now, what happens next? So, one
thing I'm really interested in is sure,
you've got this PR, but how do we make
sure that before the human gets to this
PR, how do we make sure that this PR is
of high enough quality that we can
really um guarantee that the user's time
is not wasted, right? Because
I just hate and this is something that
comes up again and again and again when
I work with teams and try to get their
processes better. Like so many teams are
going, "Okay, PRs are now the
bottleneck. How do we get through the
enormous amount of PRs that we're
seeing?" And sure, we can improve the
DX, right? We can improve this view to
make sure that it's as easy to review as
possible, but we also need to make sure
that the code itself is of high enough
quality. And so for that, I recommend
using my code review skill. So after
implementation, I recommend running this
code review skill. It's somewhere in the
history here. And this code review
skill, what it does, there you go.
There's the show me that we had before.
What code review does is it first
figures out what you're diffing against,
what has changed, and it's using origin
main as the fix point here. It then
searches for any um coding standards
that you've got inside your repo. You
can see GitHub Copilot searching for the
coding standards here. It's reading the
claw.md files and it now does two
things. it spawns a sub agent to check
for those coding standards. So it's
checking whether the actual um code that
was implemented corresponds to the stuff
you've written that you know we need to
do it this way we need to do it X way
and I have a list of coding standards
that I keep in my repo that I append to
when things go wrong and we'll talk
about that in a minute. Then it's also
doing a spec check. So it's doing a
check against what I actually specified
using this conversation history making
sure that the thing that was built is
actually the thing that we wanted. And
what this means is because we're doing
these in sub aents these are clean
context windows. It means that the agent
drops a lot of its preconceptions we get
a new trajectory in the conversation and
is often able to surface stuff that you
hadn't considered before. And so looks
like our spec came back with no
findings. That's nice. and standards.
There's one judgment call duplicated
beat learning goal relation
configuration in DB beat services
operations. Okay, interesting. If we go
into GitHub copilot, we can see that
this was created as a commit here. So,
dduplicate beat relation query. Let's
review here and we can see that okay,
what it did was before we had a bit of
duplicated configuration between two
calls and it turned that into an as uh
kind of object here to figure that out.
That's nice. That's a nice little
change. And all of that happens, code
review happens before the user goes to
review. I think there's this prevailing
idea with uh AI code review that the
code review should then go to the human
to figure out what should change next or
whether we should actually implement
these things. In other words, the output
of most code review skills is comments.
I believe that code review is kind of
part of the implementation flow and so
it's kind of like a traditional red
green refactor. The implementer agent is
responsible for doing the red green like
just getting the thing working and then
the refactor is done by these review
agents that I've been working with. So
that means we end up with a PR that is
pretty nice to review. And actually
looking down the code here, I can see,
okay, there's something that is sort of
stressing me out a little bit. It's not
anything to do with a command here or
any of this stuff. I just had a little
look and I realized, oh, okay, this
where is this? this RPC layer here. I've
got a feeling that this is not very type
safe. Had a little look inside the code
and I realized ah that's pretty gross
actually. I really don't like that. And
so what I realized is I want to I don't
want to block this PR but as part of
this PR merging or maybe uh in a stack I
want to take a look at that work take a
look at this code and maybe think about
improving the architecture of it. And
for that we have a lovely lovely skill
which is in the upkeep section which is
called improve codebase architecture.
What this skill does is it takes a look
at your repo and you can give it a
little nudge for the things you want it
to take a look at. And what it does is
it gives you a report based on the
things that it thinks you should change.
And this report can be incredibly
valuable. So if we take a look at the
report that ours generated I think it's
this one actually. Apologies for the
sudden switch to light mode. Let me take
a look at the um
actual
uh session which was inside improve
codebase architecture planning. Now what
I did was I called this with I want you
to take a look at the recent PR and see
if you can improve anything related to
the RPC. Maybe make things more type
safe. I'm not quite sure of the
architecture around that area. I want
you to take a look and offer some
suggestions. This code is stuff that I
haven't really authored myself. I've
been kind of letting the AI run wild.
I'm sure that folks have a have a strong
sense of what that feels like. An
improved codebase architecture here,
what it produces is a very nice little
diagram. The first thing it's saying is
okay, these are its recommendations down
here. Check every remote call.
Interesting. So, it flags up the uh
exact lines that it's looking for here
and it's saying the problem. The remote
adapter module is shallow at the scene.
Each adapter checks calls that it has.
It does not report a missing call. or
the final cast tells Typescript that the
adapter has every domain call. Now, this
is pretty gnarly language that it's
using here. And for this gnarly
language, I actually have another skill
that I really like. In fact, there's two
skills. There is my skill, but I'm
actually going to shout out someone
else's skill called uh PTO's skill. And
PTO here is a phenomenal skill writer
and this is one you absolutely have to
have in your library which is it
basically takes AI text and it unslops
it. So it turns it into really beautiful
maybe not sure about beautiful but it
takes out all of the AI tells from your
work and it means that horrible sort of
like um garbage like this the remote
adapter module is shallow at the seam.
you can actually get it to write it in
much planer language. So I strongly
recommend that if you're interested in
an unsloped skill. However, I do you
know I do understand what it means and I
do like this idea. Okay, we can just
reduce make it a bit more simple here
with there's a little bit down the
bottom here that I also liked as well.
So this is sort of a deep module coming
out from a lots of shallow modules. So
what I did was I decided okay let's
actually implement that. Now what does
implementing something this complicated
look like? Because the previous one I
happen to know sort of the relative
scope of what we were trying to do. I
knew that we could walk through it just
in a single session. We wouldn't need to
um do it over multiple sessions. In
other words, we just did grow with docs,
then we implemented it and then we used
code review at the bottom. But for
things that might cross over multiple
sessions or might spiral out of control
in terms of the size, then I recommend a
different approach. You can do grill
with docs and or in our case we've kind
of got something pretty workable
already. We can go improve codebase
architecture and then turn that into a
spec. Now the point of a spec is if we
take a look at our GitHub issues in
here, we can take a look at this spec
that I created which is uh I think it is
here. Make the CVM RPC call mappings and
forwarding type save. What I ended up
doing was I turned that really nice um
sort of diagram here, this uh spec of
what was supposed to be done and I
turned it into a proper spec where we
had user stories. We have a solution
here and a problem as well as a bunch of
implementation decisions and kind of
specking out exactly what I wanted from
the work and then we call a different
skill under that to create the actual
tickets that correspond to making the
spec reality. So this spec is
essentially the destination and these
tickets are the journey and what I did
is all of this was done inside one
session inside the planning session and
you can see that it's published two
independent tickets right at the bottom
and I've been using two tickets there
and then in a separate session I did the
implementation and this implementation
will be quite new to anyone who's used
my skills before which is I used a skill
called implement
spec and I just sent it the spec. So
what it did first is it went and mapped
the tickets dependencies and then opened
a draft PR and then those two tickets it
turned out were independent so they
could be worked on by themselves
independently. And so what it did was it
worked them independently on separate
work trees and branches. So we have
parallelization here. We're able to
spawn out multiple sub aents to put them
on different work trees. GitHub Copilot
is handling all of this for me. And then
it rebased them together and yeah,
merged into draft PR. Everything's
working. Uh merge adapter ticket. There
we go. And then it did a code review at
the end. So one thing that this skill
does really nicely is we can actually
take a look at the skill in a minute is
it runs an exploration agent. It runs
everything it can in parallel and then
it code reviews it at the end and fixes
everything it finds.
So once we get to there, there we go.
You can see the code review running. You
can see it fixing the review findings.
We ended up with a pretty nice PR that
we can actually just stack on top of the
other one. So here is the original PR.
Oh no, here we go. No, this is the the
proper PR. It closes all of the tickets
that we created. Closes the spec. It
closes the each individual ticket. And
then we get a nice thing that we can
actually merge on top of it in order to
make our operations type safe in future.
So that's the flow is if you want to
make your code actually um function
better over time and clear up some of
the slop, you end up with these nice
architecture reviews that you can just
keep working on. But what about if you
want to actually take this approach,
take this unslopping approach and apply
it to your own agent, to your agents
environment. What do you do then? Well,
I've got a new skill. And this new skill
is called retro. Retro, take the four
most recent sessions and do a retro on
them. And a retro comes from the word
retrospective where at the end of a
piece of work, you look back over what
you've done and see what you can
improve. And so agents are pretty good
at this because a lot of agents have
access to their own session history. So
does GitHub copilot. So it reads the you
know most recent sessions reads the
implementation session the architecture
session looks for all the session
artifacts and the session checkpoints
and then it suggests a bunch of ideas.
So we can see the implement spec run
created PR directly from the active
feature branch rather than its intended
base. So there was a little bit of
confusion there with the agent. So it's
saying you probably need to change the
skill a little bit. Tighten
implementation specs integration branch
step resolve the target base before
creating anything. Then it's also
looking at tool economy. So it's seeing
are the tools that we're calling token
efficient enough and also we're looking
at navigation steps here. So this retro
is something that's really exciting to
me. It's something I'm going to continue
working on and it builds on the main
flow of the skills here where you grill
you then uh either go and create spec
and tickets to work it over multiple
different sessions multiple sub aents.
You then go to implement it. You then do
a code review on it. And then you do a
retro where you look for opportunities
to do better next time. I'm excited
about the growth of these skills. I'm
excited about how so many people are
going to get to work with them. And I
just I love being able to package up my
processes and send them to you. You can
install them. You can modify them,
fiddle with them. And I think that's so
so exciting for this era that we live
in. I love it. So, thank you so much for
watching. Have a great rest of Copilot
Day. See you very soon. When an agent
makes a change, you'll want to review
it, run it, and see it. The good news is
that you can do all three without
leaving the app. Normally, those three
jobs would mean bouncing between your
editor, a terminal window, and a web
browser. Here, they live side by side as
built-in panels, so checking an agent's
work is quick instead of a chore.
A diff shows exactly what changed with
additions in green and deletions in red,
so nothing is a mystery. And you're not
just a passive reader. You can accept
changes, leave comments, or ask Copilot
to adjust. This is where you stay the
decision maker, and nothing is final
until you say so. That's the tight loop
and the whole point. The faster you can
go from change to confidence, the more
comfortable you'll be letting agents
help. Once we're happy, we can accept
the change right here and create a PR
and move on. Having review, run, and
preview side by side is exactly what
makes agent made changes feel safe
instead of scary because you've seen the
proof with your own eyes. Next time an
agent edits your code, open the diff,
run the tests, and preview it live
before you accept. Give it a try with
GitHub Copilot app at gh.io/app.
Hi everyone, my name is Julia and I'm a
PM on the GitHub copilot team. Today we
are super excited. We're going to be
talking about hydrofusion. With me today
I have Ashna. Ashna is an applied
scientist. She's on the Microsoft
research team and you were one of the
lead researchers for project hydra
fusion. I'm super excited to have you
Ashna and welcome.
>> Hey Julia and hi everyone. I'm so
excited to be here.
>> Um very big day. Last Friday we
announced hydro fusion and it was a big
bang. Satia even posted about it. So, I
think Friday definitely went by in a
blur. Um, for everyone on this call who
hasn't heard about hydroofusion yet, um,
I know James talked about it in his
section previously and but we just
wanted to make sure everyone is aware.
So, hydrofusion right now is in the
GitHub copilot CLI. If you do slash
models, you're now able in experimental
mode, you're able to find hydrofusion.
It's in a research preview. You're just
able to give it any task you want and it
will start doing and helping you out. It
will show you whatever pattern execution
pattern it pick. In this case, it picked
single. It's doing all of the things for
you. It will start implementing it and
helping you out. It will of course also
show you very regularly how many tokens
or AI credits it has been used. Um so
all of these things that we are already
aware of. Um but before we going to go a
little bit more into details Ashna from
your perspective what is hydrofusion
what is it all about and what are some
of the problems it's helping our dev
community out there
>> yeah so um hydrofusion is an
orchestration system so we take in a
task we understand what the capabilities
of the task are what are the
requirements we score it we send it to
one of the workflows that Julia just
showed which is single cascade critic
and we get the final outcome. So we no
longer choose the best model for your
task but we choose the right workflow
which is a composition of different
models.
>> Okay, very interesting. So it sounds a
little bit like model routing. Um can
you explain a little bit more about why
do we even need model routing? Why
couldn't I just go in pick the best
model that I know that is there for my
task and why couldn't I just do it this
way?
>> Yeah, because best is the property of
the model and task combined. To take an
example, we ran a routing algorithm on
100 software 500 software engineering
tasks. 318
um were solved by both the frontier
model and a cheap model. 53 were solved
by a frontier model alone and 29 were
solved by the cheap model alone. Now the
router has two jobs. One is to identify
the cheaper model can do the 318 tasks
and we no longer need the more expensive
model for the task that both models can
solve. The second job is to push the
quality and go beyond the 318 and cover
the 82 tasks that we have in hand. Now
that pushes the router ceiling to 400
tasks out of 500 and that is the ceiling
of the router. So selection has a
ceiling but composition doesn't and
that's where hydrofusion comes in. We
try to go uh to the 100 unresolved tasks
and we try to stretch the quality over
there.
>> Super interesting. So you're taking a
little bit away the complexity from the
end users. they don't have to worry
about it. But you're even able to make
it smarter in a way and picking the
right route, right?
>> Yeah. And to look into the workflows a
bit, it's um I I guess every developer
on this call is already doing this on a
day-to-day basis. You take the task, you
decide which model is good for the task,
you understand the outcome, and you try
to take it to the strong model if you're
not satisfied with the outcome. So today
you are the router, you are the reviewer
and you are the escalation system. Hydro
fusion combines these into three
workflows and does it for you. So if you
have a simple task, you take the request
and you only need a simple model for the
end toend execution.
For more difficult tasks, you start with
a model and you look at the outcome of
the model. If it is not good enough, it
goes to a stronger model and decid and
the stronger model decides whether the
outcome is not good enough and it does
the task for you and you get the best
output. For more harder tasks where
quality actually matters is where the
critic workflow comes in where we start
with a strong model and we have a cheap
reviewer which reviews the plan of the
strong model and iterates on it giving
you the best quality. Now here is the
design decision that we had to make that
the critic model um is always supposed
to review the outcome and not do the
edits directly because once the critic
model starts imposing and not reviewing
it tries to take over the main model.
>> Very interesting. So all of these
patterns um we already do in a way na
naturally but basically hydrofusing is
doing this for you. ideally staying with
single um but sometimes it picks um a
different model and uses it as well. So
help me understand if you're picking or
choosing another model in the mix how
can it still stays cheaper than picking
two models after each other.
>> Yeah, because we are very selective and
most of the requests actually just need
the single workflow. um it's up to the
task and the requirement of the task
that we decide whether it needs to go to
a stronger model for additional review
or not.
>> Very cool. Thank you so much. Um I've
heard you also have a de demo with with
you. So let's jump in.
>> Let's get into the demo. So um here we
see three views the same repository and
we have Opus 5, Fable 51 and Hydrofusion
compared side to side. uh below you'll
see the cost in terms of AI units and we
see that for a simple query hydrofusion
routes it to the single workflow we we
don't need a strong model for adding
type hints and dock strings and you can
see the cost difference in the bottom.
Now if we go to the next query
we again there is a simple query which
is renaming a config key across the
repo. Again a simple change we don't
really need a strong model. So
hydrofusion routes it to the single
workflow and we are resolving it with a
soul. So again saved cost for this and
it's automatically doing it behind the
scenes.
Now come to a slightly ambiguous and a
harder query which is fixing the failing
retry tests. So Hydroofusion picks the
cascade workflow.
It starts with a simple model like Luna
and it reviews whether Luna actually
made the required edits. Now a stronger
model like soul comes in and checks it
and says oh it's I I don't like the
output and I uh will redo it. So we get
the final outcome from soul instead.
And if you look at the cost, we we are
still lower in spite of using the two
models.
Now comes the harder query where quality
really matters which is for this
particular query we are doing some o
changes and hydrofusion picks the critic
workflow. So we start with a model like
opus 5 and we have a reviewer model like
soul which revises the output of opus 5
and gives you the best outcome.
Now note that hydrofusion decides to
spend the cost where it matters the
most. So where quality matters we do
spend more because we want to make sure
that the best quality is delivered.
Now for the four queries that we just
ran, if you look at the session overall
and compare with Opus 5 and Fable 51,
we in spite of spending more for the
critic workflow which is the fourth
task, we are still 42% less than Opus 5
and 47% less than Fable 51 in terms of
cost while delivering the same quality.
>> Awesome. Very cool. And the cool thing
is the end user doesn't have to worry
about it. I basically just picked
hydroofusion. It does it for me. It
either picks single, it picks the
cascade one or the critique one. And as
we've seen with critique, yes, it picks
or does another review because it knows
the quality here really matters. And
that's where it's still cheaper than
Fable 5.1, but it gets the quality that
it is needed in that use case scenario
here.
>> Yeah. All right. So we launched um
public um publicly now but it's um
considered a um research preview. So
before we go live I know we tested it
internally but can you walk us a little
bit about or talk a little bit about
what are some additional tests? How are
you evaluating? How did you know there
was such excitement behind hydrofusion?
So what are some of the things that you
and the team looked at?
>> Yeah. So the way we evaluate um hydro
fusion is really running it on a few
benchmarks which is a combination of
open-source benchmark and our own own
internal benchmark which is checkpoint
bench. So um the two open source
benchmarks that we picked are terminal
bench 21 and deep sui and what we do is
we fix the frontier model for all the
tasks and we compare it with hydrofusion
in terms of cost and quality. So if you
see for terminal bench 21 we are at 67%
lower cost than opus 5 at 5 point
quality difference. For Deep Suite, we
are at similar quality than Opus 5 and
36% lower cost. For Checkpoint Bench,
which is our internal data set, we are
at similar quality as Opus 5 again at
65% lower cost. Super interesting. I
mean, I would I know we don't have that
much time left. Um, but you talked about
two public benchmarks here. You also
talked about Checkpoint Pinch, which is
an internal benchmark. Can you tell or
tease a little bit about why do we also
rely on internal benchmarks and why this
number is also super exciting for us?
>> Yeah, so there are a few things why we
had to create our own internal
benchmark. One is public benchmarks look
at the average of model performance and
what we care about is the disagreement
between the models. The second is most
of the public benchmarks are single turn
and they are mostly saturated. Real life
conversations are more multi-turn. So we
go back and forth and we um try to um
look at the agentic conversation in a
multi-turn way. And the third one is
contamination. So for our benchmark, we
fix the um uh code to the commit right
before the fix and we cut off the
network access to code host. So now the
agent cannot clone the repository and
look at the commit that fixed the bug
beforehand.
So while we want to keep hill climbing
on the public benchmarks to compare
against the frontier models, it is very
important for us to stay close to actual
user queries which is why we need the
internal data set.
>> Mhm. Awesome. And is this also the set
whenever a new model drops that you're
evaluating and trying to make sure or is
should it be part of the new set of
hydrofusion models? Um, is this the same
setup you go through for any potential
new models?
>> It's the same strategy. Um, the
benchmarks keep evolving. So, we have to
keep up with the benchmarks and the
models and um, yeah, every week it's
evolving and we we need to keep up.
>> Yeah, makes sense. All right. Um, this
being said, Hydroofusion is out today.
Try it. It's make sure it's um, you're
doing SLEexperimental. It's an
experimental research preview. Um, if
you have any feedback and we are
actively listening. We have an external
discussion post out there. Make sure
you're leaving any feedback that you
might have. Uh, what's next? We are
already working on the GitHub copilot
app integration, VS Code integration as
well. We already have a few u UX
improvements queued up as well um, based
on all of the great feedback that we've
already seen from the community out
there. So please let us know. Um and
yeah Ashna, do you have any final words?
>> Yeah, I think the interesting question
changed. For the last two years, we've
been focusing on what is the best model
that is coming and the frontier keeps
evolving. But what we want to focus on
is the orchestration.
Again, selection has a ceiling, but
composition doesn't. And that's where we
are taking this next with orchestration.
So you can stop being a router, a
reviewer and an escalation system and go
back to building what you you care
about.
>> Thank you so much Ashna and we will be
in the chat so leave any questions that
you might have. And with this being
said, I'm handing back to the studio.
Let's explore what makes GitHub Copilot
app special.
The C-pilot app is the agent native home
for your work on GitHub right on your
desktop. Agents can go beyond just
generating code. They can run builds and
tests, create PRs, and even access
external services. You can control their
level of autonomy depending on your
needs and scenarios. You can create
sessions on your repos with each session
using work trees to be independent of
one another. And you can even use agents
to help you manage your PR in CI flow.
There's of course lots more to explore.
As always, the best way to learn is to
get in and play with the tool yourself.
You can download it at gh.io/app.
Try it on a repo you know, maybe with a
task that's been sitting on your backlog
for a while now. You might be surprised
how much it gets done while you're still
learning the tool.
Hey folks, welcome back. That
hydrofusion model looks amazing,
especially at that at the cost. Cost is
super important. Uh, but something else
that I want to show you um, really
quickly is this little item right here.
This, let me get this in the I feel like
we're doing home shopping. This is This
is the Logitech. This is the Logitech MX
Creative Console. This at the top is the
Logitech MX keypad. Now, what if you
could use this device to see all of your
running Copilot sessions, easily move
between them, toggle the mic on and off,
enable, disable MCP servers. You can do
that and you can do that today. So, you
can get this device today and you can
get it working with GitHub Copilot.
Today, we're going to do that here in
just a little bit. We're going to get
this thing up and running, show you
exactly how that works and how you can
increase your productivity. But speaking
of productivity, what I want to do now
is go over to Megan to show you what's
new and how you can use GitHub Copilot,
where you work today in both Teams and
Slack. Megan,
>> hello everyone. Thank you Burke for the
intro. Uh, as Brooke said, today I'm
going to talk a little bit more about uh
how you can use Copilot from multiple
surfaces uh and spend a little time on
our Slack surface specifically. Uh the
keynote today, James and Pierce talked
about and showed some of the value of
using it in Slack, but I just want to
spend a little bit more time building
something together and uh so we'll just
we'll bake the cake together. Uh so what
we're looking at here is my fitness
booking app. This is just like a fun app
that I've been building that's a way for
users to book local fitness classes. Um,
and I want to show some of the history
of like what I've done inside Slack.
I've predominantly developed this app
inside of Slack, which is very fun and
it's useful when I'm on the go and I can
just kick things off. Uh, and so an
example of the types of things I've
built here in Slack. If you jump into
this code channel, which is a new Slack
feature in their uh, Slack code
offering, you can see that I'm going
back and forth with another PM on my
team, Tim, and uh, we're designing this
new ability to see trending classes
inside of the app. And that way, it kind
of gives the user some signal on like
what are some fun classes that, you
know, people are really enjoying. And
so, uh, I I kicked this off, but then I
asked Tim for his feedback. Tim comes in
and says like, okay, looking at this,
like, can we hide the trending pills?
It's a bit too noisy. And then right
here in Slack, you can see the live app
renderer, which makes it really easy to
iterate quickly on these kind of like
more front-end workflows. Uh, and the
GitHub copilot harness is powering all
of this. So, the harness is returning
all of the um all the work and it's
allowing us to see it and iterate on it
directly. And what I love about this is
like this experience is really nice uh
inside Slack, especially if you're
working with a team member. We also
offer it in Microsoft Teams, but it's uh
especially powerful when you can use it
across all surfaces. So I can open this
inside of GitHub and I'll show that flow
while we do the live uh the live
building together. And I can open it on
mobile. It I can pick it up, grab the PR
and changes and pick it up inside VS
Code or the GitHub Copilot app. And so
this just allows me to build wherever is
natural to me and kind of start work and
finish it wherever I happen to be at
that time. Uh so one thing I wanted to
do together while uh I have you all is
build some sort of new feature. Uh I
kind of wish this was like a birectional
like situation where you guys could
suggest features. I think that'd be very
fun. But the one I just came up with the
top of my head right now is let's build
a visual log uh of every class that I've
been to so that the user has this like
self-personaliz personalization. Uh and
so I'm going to kick that off and show
you live just like how fast this is. I
think that's one of the things I'm
enjoying the most is, you know, on the
GitHub side, we've done a lot to make
the experience really good in the cloud
sandbox environment. And so you can kind
of like feel that experience when you're
using it and developing on it. So I've
kicked it off. GitHub's kind of telling
me what it's doing. So the first thing
it said to me is like, hey, I'm starting
your cloud environment. And then it
said, I'm reading the chat history to
get some context of what we're doing.
Uh, and then from there it opens this
code channel which is a way to just kind
of keep all of its metadata about this
feature inside one place in Slack. You c
you can obviously just have it like
paste in the thread as well. This is
kind of just like a a user choice thing.
But then GitHub saying to me, okay, I
opened this uh channel here for us to
collaborate together. And if I come into
this channel, you can kind you can see
some new metadata that you probably
aren't used to seeing inside of Slack
and Teams, which is now we see the like
repo it's working on or the branch it's
working on, the repo it's working in.
And then there's this open session which
I will follow and show you all how I can
see all of this inside github.com. And
so it is nice to have it all in context.
I'm already inside this repo. I can see
the other work that's being done in this
repo. Um, I can also see it on mobile,
which I wanted to attempt to demo live,
though I know it won't render great, but
um, our mobile app is rendering my cloud
sessions, and so I can see them all and
am able to follow its progress on the
go.
And then from here, I can kind of see
what the history is. If someone else
came in, it would show me their work as
well. I can see what the spend is of the
session, which I know is like very
important um, for a lot of users to be
able to calibrate their own spending and
keep an eye on it. And then inside the
slack channel, the last thing I can see
is the model. Uh you can obviously
change that model, but we have our
default model here. And so the uh
implementation plan is just walking
through what the agent is working on
similar to what you would expect in
other GitHub copilot clients. Uh the
runtime is all the same. So the
experience that you get inside the CLI
or inside the GitHub copilot app should
be very similar to what you see inside
Slack and Teams. So, right now it's just
working on, you know, building this out.
And while it's doing that, I have a
couple of my already baked cakes that I
wanted to walk through because I think
this experience is fun. And this like
use case of a um like a fitness booking
app is I think a really fun one to just
be able to like quickly visualize what
what's going on, what is the agent
doing. So, right before I jumped onto
this stream, like literally right before
I asked uh Patrick, who you'll see later
in the room, I said like, "Hey, what's a
feature you would want?" And he's like,
"I feel like a really good feature is
like, what's the promos? Like, what is a
class that's cheap this week?" Because
that might influence, you know, me
changing my routine. And so, I just
quickly shot a note to GitHub like,
"Hey, build this thing, but give me five
examples so that I can just or sorry,
five, give me three examples that I can
just choose from." Um, and I I said like
an example is like a $5 promo on
Wednesdays for classes. Uh, and so it
rendered a couple of options for me. Uh,
the first one is this like campaign
banner, which I think I like the most.
Uh, and then the second option is this
almost like this very salesy. This
reminds me of like some sort of like
Uber Eats, you know, type promo, which I
feel like is maybe not the aesthetic I'm
going for, but it's really fun to have
this level of iteration because then I
can just add Patrick and be like, "Hey,
you know, you asked for this feature.
What are your thoughts? Is this what you
were expecting or not?" And uh you know,
from there I can pick it up with the
agent. I can also see the code diff
inside of um oh, apparently I can't
right now, but I will show it in my
other channel. um when uh the agent will
by default show the code diff and then
you can open a PR which I feel like is
you know a very common workflow of where
I would want to go from here. So let's
do that live and then I can kind of show
the continuity throughout all of GitHub.
Let's check back in now on on the the
session we kicked off around doing the
class history. So, I'm just checking in
on it and it's uh working on the
complete history experience. The test
data that I have in the app for this has
like 12 attendance records. I'm going to
quickly show you all just what it looks
like today so we have a reference point
when it makes this change. So, here's
our app today that I briefly showed
earlier. Um the profile experience has
this like classes remaining because it's
based on like a monthly quota, but
there's no real insight into like okay,
you know, what value did I get from this
subscription? And so part of the the
thing we're trying to add is just the
the history to kind of make it fun to be
like here's all the things you did, you
know, since you're paying for your
monthly subscription. Um, and then I
want to show one code diff while we're
in this channel so you can
see what I'm saying. Uh, very similar to
the GitHub PRS view where it's broken
down by file and each change. Um, this
obviously would match. Let me see if I
have an open PR. Yeah, let's look at the
open PR for this. um they should be
identical because it's just the diff
inside the sandbox um being opened into
a PR. And so you can imagine the
continuity here in terms of, you know,
in my repo I have copilot reviewing it
by default. And so I am doing this work
from Slack, but I'm getting all of the
benefits of my like enterprise code
review inside of GitHub. And all of
these things have a great integration
across them, which I feel like as a user
is nice to not have to think about like,
oh, I need to copy and paste context
from here to this agent to this thing.
You know, the the sessions just flow. uh
whether it's from mobile to uh or or
from Slack to my local you know desktop
client uh or terminal and then into
github.com. It's just that continuity
that I think as a user is really nice so
that it just happens for me. It's not
something I have to manually think
about.
This is the the fun of live demos. Uh it
should just magically appear with
something shortly. Um there we go. That
was great timing. um as I was doing
that. Uh okay. So it looks like we are
opening some issues based on the
history. Uh which isn't exactly what I
wanted. Uh but we can we can easily
redirect here. Oh, okay. We're doing a
rendering. Awesome. So we're thinking
through what each of the issues are and
how we need to address it. And then it's
it also appears that the agent is going
to make the change. So hopefully that
pops up here while we're doing it live.
Um, but luckily we had those uh backup
examples in case it doesn't finish in
time. And I'll take one more look at
this uh live session. So you can just
kind of see the experience of as it's
going through here. Uh I can see like
the additional agent logs if I want more
details as to what the agent's doing.
Obviously in Slack it doesn't make a ton
of sense to like render all of these
things, but it's really nice for me to
have that option to be able to go and
see its full train of thought, see what
commands it's running on the sandbox,
etc.
So, we did talk about Microsoft Teams
and I want to make sure that I at least
mention that. Uh, one of the things that
I've been really enjoying since we
released uh these new integrations in
the last few weeks is that inside
Microsoft Teams, we're using it a lot in
meetings and that's been a really fun
use case. Specifically, as we're like
talking about status updates, we just
add the GitHub agent to our teams
meetings and then we're creating issues.
we are like you know saying hey GitHub
go investigate this problem that we are
hearing about in this meeting. I've also
been doing it uh with some of our
customers just to like be able to show
them how the integration works and how
they should leverage it. And it's been a
very fun like direct demo to be like hey
look we can I can show you right here
for this open source repo like like the
copilot SDK or the copilot CLI what the
major changes are and that all happens
inside of this team's meeting. Uh so
that's been a really cool surface for us
to kind of explore. Okay, so demo gods
have blessed us and just in time we have
this rendering of the history class
history and you can see that the the the
model has made some creative sales pitch
here around every class leaves a mark.
Um but it's showing over time kind of
like the history of what classes um
where like you know yoga, pilates,
cycling, and strength are called out. Um
this is like kind of what I had in mind.
I think we could definitely iterate on
it. This fake data looks very fake, but
uh that's not what the demo is about.
The demo is about showing you how
powerful uh GitHub Copilot is in
multiple surfaces and meeting you where
you are. And so I think this timing
worked out perfectly. I could not have
planned it better where you can kind of
see this endto-end flow and how fast it
feels, how connected it is um to our
existing github.com experience. Uh and I
hope that you all try it out. I hope you
give us lots of feedback. I'm available
on Twitter. A lot of us are or X. Um, as
well as LinkedIn. Feel free to just like
share all of your sentiment using the
thing. We're making it better every day.
And, uh, hope that regardless what
client you're using from GitHub C-Pilot
that it's doing the job and you're
loving the experience. So, with that
said, I will hand it back to Burke.
Thank you.
>> Thank you so much, Megan. I love GitHub
Copilot in Teams and Slack. You know,
for a long time work happens in Teams
and Slack and then you have to get that
from there over to GitHub Copilot.
There's a lot of context switching and
the answer was well install an MCP
server in Teams uh excuse me GitHub
copilot so you can access Teams or Slack
and now it's just in the place where
you're already collaborating with other
people. Um, and someone once said that
some of these interfaces are perfect for
inter for iterating with agents, and I
tend to agree. Now, one of the things
that we released this last week was the
official Visual Studio Code documentary.
This is a film that has been several
years in the making. It started quite a
while ago. It chronicles the entire
story of Visual Studio Code, where it
came from, how it came to be. Uh, it's
fascinating. It's a fascinating story.
It goes back a long ways. It's got a lot
of twists and turns and we've got a
trailer for you. Check it out.
>> Something was happening in the developer
world and that was because of the web.
We knew that if we wanted to stay
relevant with developers, we had to do
something.
>> So, our whole effort at that point was
to try to build this editor to see if it
could work in the browser and then go
from there. Literally, they want to be
able to go from their brain down their
arms to their fingers without having to
think.
>> Yeah. So, there were a lot of um
interesting challenges. It would just
crash, right? It wouldn't give errors.
It would crash.
>> The browser be a little bit early. You
cannot just theorize. You don't become
relevant with nice architecture
diagrams. You become relevant when you
have something to hand you can ship and
you can demo. It was a showcase for
Electron. It was a showcase for
TypeScript. It was a showcase that a
cross-platform app at that time 10 years
ago could do the stuff that it did. But
then co-pilot completions came. I think
it marked a real transition for us from
a mature market understanding what
people want and need to they actually
don't really know.
>> Hi, I'm Tyler Leanhart. You may remember
me from uh my oneliner in the VS Code
documentary and also my college
submission to a film festival. I'm going
to be talking to you about BY and
multi-agent harness in VS Code. So, what
does that even mean? Uh well, it's
basically two kinds of freedom, right?
Copilot, as you know, already provides
multi- uh models, models from uh various
different vendors, OpenAI, Anthropic,
etc. Uh but uh you don't have to get
your models directly from a co-pilot
subscription. We also support BY and
that means bring your own key. So that
means using the compute that you already
have or if you're working inside of a
private or air gap network uh that also
works or if you run uh models locally on
your machine, you can al also bring
those in to the C-pilot uh agent
harness. Uh but that's not the only bit
of flexibility that we have in VS Code
and the Copilot agent. Uh in VS Code
itself, you have uh you have an agent
choice as well. So we have C-Pilot as
our as our default agent. Uh we think
it's pretty great. Uh but if you also
want to try out some other harnesses,
we've got Claude and Codeex available
for you to try out. Uh so you can keep
using the tools that feel natural to
you. uh and you have one UI, one place
uh to interact with those agents, and
that's VS Code. So, what does any of
that mean? I feel like I just need to
show you a demo. And so, let me tell you
what I'm going to show you. So, we've
got three different harnesses. We got
Copilot, Claude, and Codeex. And I want
to show you uh BY stuff uh and also like
how these things uh can be integrated
with with not only Copilot as the model
provider, but other providers as well.
So copilot uh copilot harness is going
to use bio uh via open router. So I'm
going to provide an open router API key
and we'll get models from that and use
that in the copilot harness. Our claude
agent is going to use uh anthropic uh an
anthropic API key. Um and then the
codeex uh agent harness is going to
actually have chatpt signin. In other
words, a catchp subscription to use uh
in the codeex in the codeex agent inside
of VS code. Uh, so that's a lot, but
I've got six minutes to do it. And so,
let's just go ahead and get started. I'm
going to hit hit uh click to get that
going. All right, so VS Code, you know
it, I know it, I love it. Uh, I'm going
to do this demo from inside of the
agents window, which you can get at the
very top of the editor window. We can
open an agents window. This is our like
kind of uh top level view of all of your
agent sessions, your chat sessions. Uh,
when you get here, you can see that I'm
not actually signed in with GitHub or a
co-pilot subscription today. Um, and I
need to add models. Now, I could sign in
and get my C-pilot subscription, but
that's not what this talk is about yet.
I want to actually add models through a
different mechanism. So, I'm going to
add models, and I'm going to go to open
router, and I'm going to tab over, copy
my open router API key,
JK, and put that here. And you can see
that brings in just a ton of models
here, right? Great. So, uh, we're going
to hide all of those because I really
don't want to be overwhelmed with how
many models they have. And then we're
going to add, uh, we'll just have Haiku
there. Okay, sound good. Uh so from
there I can go to the model picker in
the agent harness uh in the agents
window here and I can say uh what kind
of uh who are you
and what tools do you have?
Now what's important to note is that
like the copilot agent, the claude agent
and the codeex agent, they all bring
their own prompts and they bring their
own tools as well. So uh they're going
to function differently. Uh but that is
the beauty of being able to try all of
them right within VS Code. So this one
says, "Hey, I'm the co-pilot SDK uh in
VS Code." Great. So I'm going to make a
new chat. Hit the agent harness drop
down here and pick Claude. Uh now I've
already hooked up a Claude API key uh
this way. And you can see uh in my
claude settings file here, I'm using uh
this API key helper here so I don't uh
leak my anthropic API key. Uh and so
then I'm going to ask Claude the same
question as before again using Haiku
because I only got six minutes to go
through this demo. And you can see that
Claude says that it's Claude obviously
and uh and tools that it has. Uh and
then finally I wanted to show you codeex
as well. Uh so when you pick codeex
you've got the option of course to sign
into GitHub. We'll cover that in a
second. Uh but you can sign in with your
chatpt subscription as well. So I will
uh go ahead and pick uh my chatpt
subscription here. It's a it's a free
subscription, right? The the one that
like so many people have uh and I'm
going to go to my phone in order to get
a code uh because that's the only way to
log into things these days. Uh
great. Cool.
And then uh we'll be signed in here in a
second. Now I have to enter a phone
number. This is not right.
Let me sign in with a different account.
Yeah, I know I have another account
here.
I know you wanted to spend so much time
just watching me sign into uh to a
screen here. All right, one more code. I
promise.
There we go.
Great.
All right.
Also a phone number. That's crazy. This
didn't happen when I was doing the demo
earlier.
I'm going to give myself 30 seconds to
put this code in.
Talk about uh security here from OpenAI,
huh? It's pretty good. All right,
great. Here we go.
So now we're signed into codeex and uh I
can say
the same prompt to uh to Luna here and
we see that we have the the codeex uh
harness as well. And so I'm signed in
with my chatbt uh free skew. So last
thing I wanted to show here is that I
can also sign into my co-pilot
subscription. So I'll go ahead and do
that hopefully without having to uh put
in a bunch of random stuff.
Um,
great. So fast. We love to see it. And
uh, with this, I'm now signing with my
co-pilot subscription. And one of the
benefits of the co-pilot subscription is
that I can actually like I can interact
with all of these harnesses through my
co-pilot subscription. So, I get access
to everything. Uh, I can say hi here now
using uh
using Luna from my co-pilot
subscription. And also you can see
there's a section for uh co-pilot here
uh in claude and also in of course uh
copilot right so I can use all of these
harnesses with a co-pilot subscription
and that's uh one thing that I think is
really powerful about a copilot
subscription is that you can you can
actually play with all of these
harnesses uh without having to uh have
multiple subscriptions across different
um different places. So, uh, all right.
Well, okay. Hey, that that was actually,
uh, not so bad all things considered
with the with text messages and whatnot.
So, just to recap what you what you just
saw in that demo, the co-pilot harness,
I first added an open router API key uh,
showing that we have by uh, support in
the co-pilot harness. Then in the cloud
agent we added uh an anthropic API key
and used uh anthropic uh API key compute
through the cloud agent. And in the
codeex agent we added a chatp
subscription to sign in and use the
codeex agent. Now of course you can
configure all three of those agents with
their own subscriptions and their own
ways of getting models or you could keep
it simple and just use a copilot
subscription which would give you access
to all of those all from within VS Code.
So, uh, that is my biggest takeaway in
all of this. Uh, go forth and go play,
uh, and have fun with, uh, with these
different, uh, agents. Uh, they're all
powered by something called, uh, agent
host protocol, which my friend Patrick
is going to tell you about in a little
bit. Uh, but, uh, yeah, Claude and
Codeex are a couple of harnesses we
support today. Uh, we're thinking about
expanding those to to harnesses beyond
those uh, those two uh, third party
harnesses. But uh but yeah, take a look
at this space. It's it's really fun,
really cool. Uh and yeah, that's uh
that's actually uh all I have to to say.
Um my demo actually was a lot faster
than before. So um sweet.
I guess I will just pass it on over to
the next segment, which is a very cool
video. Just you wait. With VS Code, you
have a fleet of agents ready to help you
plan, build, test, and deploy your apps.
Now, for the longest time, agent
sessions have been tied to the window
that started them. But the team thought
to themselves, "What if your agents
could keep running after you close the
folder? What if you could pick them up
on another machine or even on the web?"
The agent host capabilities in VS Code
brings you all of this and more,
enabling the ability to run sessions on
their own dedicated process. So, it's
not tied to any window, any client, or
any machine. The session is still
running. It didn't miss a beat because
the session lives in the host process.
Now, when I'm working across multiple
sessions and projects, I live in the
agents window. So, let's open that up.
And there it is, the exact same live
session. It's not a copy. So, no matter
where I'm working, the session is there
for me. With agent host, you can take
your sessions wherever you go. And from
here, I can connect to my agent host
machine and see the same exact sessions
all still running.
>> Hey everyone, my name is Patrick
Nicolet. I'm a product manager on the
GitHub copilot team. I specifically work
on the Copilot SDK and runtime, which
gives me an ability to work across many
surfaces and accomplish many tasks
related to the needs that agents are
supposed to live up to and be
responsible for in the future as we make
this transition to this exciting new
world. Before I I dive into the core
topic which is the agent host protocol,
I want to touch a little bit on the
copilot SDK and how it relates to agent
host protocol in particular and some of
the investments that we're making over
here at GitHub and some of the exciting
new features that will be landing in the
coming months here. For context, the
GitHub copilot SDK is our latest cutting
edge modern runtime for agents. Uh it's
used within GitHub. It's also used
across Microsoft such as the office
products to power the new agent mode
capabilities that exist in those
services as well. Uh when you think
about the actual runtime, uh it's highly
portable. It's designed to run in a
whole host of different environments, a
whole host of different constraints are
able to be applied to it. Just looking
at the basic setup guides, you can see
how diverse the the actual environments
are that you can stick the runtime in
today and then you know what additional
problems start surfacing after that
point. Um the runtime can be actually
baked on your local machine as a local
personal productivity application can be
hosted in a managed service in the cloud
can be run in process and other
applications. Um, we've recently made
some improvements to our runtime that
enable even more platforms that you can
embed it in and run it on as well. Um,
but agent host protocol comes in at a
really important intersection between
runtime capabilities and your ability to
access that runtime wherever you are.
And so something that the team has been
excited to be working on since earlier
this year, we call it the agent host
protocol. uh which is essentially a
definition for a protocol that can be
wrapped around not just the GitHub
copilot runtime uh but any runtime on
the market today or any other agentic
application. The core responsibility of
the protocol is to make sure that we can
meet users wherever they are. Um while
your hosts might be running different
runtimes at different points in time,
your ability to access that host is more
diverse than ever. uh we have laptops,
we have phones, uh sometimes we will be
introduced to new form factors like the
Duo that we saw yesterday. And I think
we're really preparing for a world where
your agents can literally run anywhere.
You can move them between locations and
more importantly, no matter which form
factor or device you have available to
you, you have access to that agent as
well. Uh, and so while we continue to
bring these capabilities into places
like VS Code and our our GitHub Cobbot
runtime as well as our other developer
services, we can already show off some
of the directions that we're already
heading and and hopefully uh you'll be
excited to see where where we're leading
to in the future. Uh, to actually show
off the agent host protocol, uh, I'm
going to use something that is is very
common in the developer circles. Uh, I
think you'll find many of us have our
own private little tail scale networks.
uh where at home, you know, I'm running
a Mac, Windows, a Linux machine at all
times. Each run is running C-pilot
agents uh as well as other agents too.
Um but I'm always limited by the fact
that I need to have a device connected
to my tail scale network to even access
those machines and really want to set
the stage to break free of even that
constraint in the new world. Uh so the
first thing that I'll do is I'll
actually just go ahead and log into my
home .naz. At this point, uh, I think
we're all going to end up with 80 terbte
Naz at home, but this is my personal one
that I use to host large files, all of
the stuff, uh, my family likes to store
and and keep a nice archive of what's
going on as well as do some coding work.
Uh, AHP comes with a variety of clients.
Um, we have built one internally that
we're using as a reference
implementation to bring capabilities
down into other surfaces. I I'll talk a
little bit about how you can play with
your own host in a little bit, but for
now I'm going to use this one we call
Copilot D. Uh Copilot D allows us to
spin up a service on any host. Um we
can, as you can see in this argument
here, open up a relay. We can define an
environment name easily. So this is my
home Linux machine. Um there's a
workspace folder. So when you actually
run the host, you know, what current
working directory is it uh traditionally
limited to? You can have more than one
if you'd like to as well. and then what
do you want to expose it on and and
what's the basic log output level. Um
when you'll see the the host spin up
itself um what it does is it produces an
environment identifier. We're just going
to go ahead and copy that. Uh in the
future we're going to make this even
friendlier and easier to use. But for
now the environment ID will be all that
we need. And we now have a host running
on this machine. Uh which doesn't mean
much by itself. But when I actually come
back to my local machine, which I'll do
over here on this tab right here, I can
actually just go right into the copilot
CLI directly, which hopefully you all
are very familiar with at this point.
Um, we'll go ahead and turn it on. And
then inside of uh upcoming builds,
there's a slash AHP command. Um, what
this allows you to do is connect to
hosts. It allows you to see sessions
across the hosts, restart them. Um
there's a few other exciting features
related to it as well, but to really
show off the core AHP concepts. What I'm
going to first do is just show you the
host command. Um we are not attached to
any host currently. The Copilot CLI
hasn't been configured to be connected
to one. But what I can do is run an AP
cloud command. Give it the environment
variable itself. And then if we flip
back over to this AHP uh tab, we should
see some connections coming in as well.
Um the nice thing is uh now I bridged
essentially my local copilot CLI
instance to the cloud uh through the
cloud to my local machine which is the
Linux box that's currently sitting at
home. I can rerun the AP hosts commands.
You can see that we are connected
externally through copilot D. You get
protocol versions, environment ids, etc.
Um, this is showing that not only am I
able to run Copilot uh locally, but we
are connected through uh my machine to
my external home machine as well. If I
want to actually use that instead, I can
simply run a / ahp use command. This
will allow me to connect directly to the
machine and it will essentially uh
enable me to create new sessions. It'll
also allow me to attach, which I'll show
you some of that that fun flexibility in
a second here. Uh if we want to start a
new session uh we can just do / ahp new.
This will uh update my interface to
actually reflect the remote host
instead. And so similar to the path that
I showed you for my workspace folder.
This is not actually anymore a directory
on my local machine. This is actually
spun up a runtime on my local Linux
server at home. It's set the current
working directory to the workspace
folder that I'm running the AP host uh
on directly and I can go ahead and
interface with the agent directly on
that machine. Um, one of the huge
benefits of this again is that even
though the runtime is running elsewhere,
these really thin external clients,
whether it's the CLI, whether it's VS
Code, uh, the GitHub Copilot app, or any
other client you'd like to build, uh,
that aligns with the protocol, can
access this uh, interface, can connect
to this system, and can actually drive
the Agentic session. Um, but it doesn't
really just stop there. Uh some of the
unique capabilities that come with
something like this uh that represent a
really nice addition to our remoting
technology is you're able to attach
multiple sessions at the same time. Um
so if I go ahead and add the AP host
onto this client as well. I run a
different command to take a look at the
sessions. Oops.
Oops.
helps if I add an S on the end. You'll
see that there is an active session
which is this E39. You'll see the
oneplus one which matches my prompts
showing that uh I can actually uh attach
to that session directly. So if I use
AHP attach
we copy this identifier right here
we should be able to bridge our sessions
together. And if you've used our
remoting technology before, uh,
typically it was poll based. It was
really forcing you into a situation
where you could have one active client,
uh, that could steer the session itself.
Now you get, um, more advanced
capabilities when it comes to real-time
replayability. Um, you get advanced
capabilities when it comes to the
playback systems and how sessions can be
portable across clients. And what this
really translates to is you get live
updates across clients as well. As you
see, I typed in one client 3 plus 3. As
soon as I hit enter, it can go to the
other client too. You can see the
response on both. Um, our core objective
and goal is to make sure as you bridge
new clients into the experience and take
them out. Each one can participate in it
to be the active driver. That way you
can transition from your laptop to your
phone, from your phone back to your
laptop, from your work machine to your
personal machine depending on the
context in which you're operating in.
But it all is made available using this
new AP protocol again that we're
embedding in our surfaces and we're also
uh sharing publicly and diving deep
looking for more ways to improve the
offering and also add more runtime
support as well. When you think about
how this translates ultimately to the
github.com experiences, one of the most
exciting things personally uh to me is
its integration into mission control. Um
our copilot dervice which again we're
looking to bring functionality directly
into our runtime as well. Uh enables you
to actually engage with these remote
execution environments directly from
mission control. And so while we look at
IDE CLI mobile, let's talk a little bit
about the web. Um, for context, mission
control is under
github.com/copilot/agents.
Uh, if you look at this main home
screen, uh, there are a few options that
should be familiar to most uh, users
that have uh, executed tasks on this
screen. But ultimately the most exciting
thing to me with AP is the fact that you
can now bring environments into the
custom dropdown for actions and execute
new sessions on your own local machines,
cloud machines, wherever they might be.
As long as they run the right AP hosts,
they connect back to mission control. It
is now a new environment that you can
execute on. So you're not constrained by
running things in actions or running
things in remote cloud environments. uh
you can actually run these on your home
machines as well to continue to bridge
uh your agent network and define where
you want to run agents most or where it
benefits you based on your current
scenario. So again, if we just simply
hit a query here, uh it should actually
route that down to my environment.
You'll see a response. And again, this
is all running off of github.com. It's
running in my private network. And as we
break free of all of our tail scale
setups uh and remove that requirement,
ultimately we'll find more flexibility
and freedom to access your agents
anywhere and again move them where you
want to go as well. For more additional
information, I I'll flash a few links on
the screen. Uh the AP uh repo is public
uh underneath Microsoft/Aenthost
protocol. We have a website with the
protocol specifications available as
well. Uh mission control is on there.
And then in addition, if you like to
play around with the host built into VS
Code, uh I left a command code agent
host there. You should be able to fire
it up uh using the latest stable edition
of VS Code. So you can start playing
with your own host right away. Thank you
all.
>> Here at Universe, it's very much choose
your own adventure based on what matters
to you.
>> There's an emphasis on just a creative
energy and vibe. GitHub Universe is the
perfect place to come to as a developer
looking to advance in your career. It's
all about getting to access the
knowledge that is needed on your teams.
There's so much more representation of
things like open-source and general
excitement around being in the developer
community that I don't necessarily feel
at other events I've been at. From the
keynote alone, I feel like I have this
step up because I got to see the new
initiatives, the new features that
GitHub is releasing.
>> This is where you get kind of a pulse on
what's happening across the broader
industry. Universe is a great
opportunity and a great place for people
to come share those ideas and to
collaborate with each other so that we
can all grow as an engineering
community.
>> The relationships that you make at these
events are going to pay dividends for
the rest of your career.
>> They're kicking us, bro.
>> Hey, what's
Burke? And I got caught a little off
guard here.
>> We just barely made it. Uh, welcome
back, folks. Thank you, Patrick. Uh, so
y'all, we're gonna spend the next uh
what do we have like two hours here and
we're gonna we're gonna build something.
But the trouble with this is always
>> like what do you build?
>> It's always hard. I remember the first
time we did this, we were like we need
to have this, you know, crazy concept.
It's going to take us all this time. We
were done in like five minutes.
>> Yeah, we finished it in five minutes.
So, and then the other thing is is that
no one's impressed anymore because you
can just build anything. And so we I was
we were thinking through this. We were
like, well,
>> like we need someone to build a killer
demo that would that we could pick up
and then build because we don't have any
good ideas of our own.
>> No, we don't.
>> But we know someone with good ideas.
>> We do.
>> We do. Uh and so we're pleased to uh to
bring Wes Boss,
who I widely consider to be the king of
demos.
>> King of demos for sure.
>> Yeah. who's going to get us kicked off
here.
>> Uh excited to to get going. I've been I
have so many ideas of things that I want
to build and uh with all the latest
models releasing. There's so many cool
things that that I can go. So, we're
going to rip for what about 20 minutes
and then uh and then we're uh I'll pass
it off to you guys to sort of pick it up
and and keep going.
>> Yep. Sounds great.
>> All right. Thanks, guys. What's up
everybody? My name is Wes. I
am going to be doing some vibe coding
for about 20 minutes here. Um, and 20
minutes not long enough for me because
like I wanted to do something that was
really cool. So yesterday obviously the
iPhone Duo was released. Um, and what I
did is I collected all of the
information about the iPhone Duo, right?
like the width and the height and all
the specs and um how thick it was. And
then I I took the uh Apple
uh where they announced it and they had
a couple photos of the internals and I
took all of that and I I plugged it into
my co-pilot and I said like do not stop
until you have a close enough or not
perfect but very good 3D model of the
iPhone Fold. And let me tell you, it
this thing ripped for like like 3 hours
and it went through like absolutely
every single piece. And I don't know if
this is actually what it looks like
inside, but I it's pretty convincing to
me. And it it works really well. Um we
can explode it. You can obviously fold
it open and closed. Uh lots of features
to that. So that was like my base of
like what I wanted to build, right? Can
I get a uh 3D model of the iPhone Duo
running in 3JS? Um, and then I thought
like like I I want to do a couple
things. First of all, I love noling
where is like where you put all the
parts in like on like a grid, right? And
these new models are just fantastic at
creating these 3D immersive exploded
experiences. Um, and then I I want to
say like there's this new API um called
HTML and canvas is like can we then
render JavaScript
on the screen of the iPhone fold? I
don't know but I'm willing to try. So
let's get into it. So uh first prompt
will be
uh I want to add a feature to the null
to the exploded view and I want to have
a nulling setting. This is we'll take
every single piece of the model and lay
it out in a grid and perfectly align
absolutely everything.
And I'm going to go ahead and let that
rip on there. While that's going, let's
take a look at um kind of all the
different pieces that we have here. All
the different color display lithium ion.
like
that's that's very impressive that you
can we can build this type of thing
entirely in 3JS. If we take a look at
the code, um it's just JavaScript on
here, right? There's there's no like uh
STLs or or fusion models or anything
like that. It's all just kind of being
uh piped in which is really cool. Um the
other thing you'll notice that I'm not
using the built-in browser uh to GitHub
Copilot right now. Um, and that's
because I want to use a an experimental
feature which is uh HTML and canvas. And
HTML and canvas, what that allows you to
do is you can take regular DOM elements
and render them into a 2D or 3D canvas
experience. So I think when we start
working on some of the apps, what we
want to do is have those rendered out to
the DOM and then paint them into the
actual device that we have here.
So what do we got here? I'm adding a
nulling toggle that lays out all model
components and is non-over overlapping.
Okay,
let that sucker run. I'm also watching
the chat here. So, if anybody has ideas
of things that we should add to this,
definitely add them into the YouTube
chat because I'll be popping those in
there as well. Um, you know what I'm
going to do while this is running? Let's
just open up a second chat here
and let's go ahead and let's start
working on the software. Right. Um,
I have the HTML and canvas skill that I
wrote. So what I did is I took the
documentation, the specification for the
HTML and canvas spec and I had that
converted into a skill and then I also
have built like six or seven demos over
the last couple months and I've taken
those demos and distilled them down into
the skill. So, I've got the skill there.
I'm going to say, um,
I want to be able to run actual apps and
software on the iPhone fold. So, let's
build some sort of structure where we
can have a home screen with app icons
and then I can open individual apps. Uh,
let's start with a simple app which is
the calculator.
All right, let's let's this sucker rip.
See how our explode view is going over
here.
Sorry, just reading the chat here.
Noling grid. All right. Oh,
baby. We've got the nulling grid there.
Um,
what I want to do is I want this more to
be like this is just like a perfect
grid. I want them to sort of box fit
into each other. The nulling grid is
great, but I want them to be organized
in a way that they sort of fit into each
other. Right now, we're just on a
perfect grid, which is determined by the
largest piece, and then the small pieces
are sort of just hanging out in a a
large spot. They should use some sort of
box fitting algorithm to nicely organize
them.
You know what I'm also going to do is I
have the agent browser skill globally
installed on my system and I I I don't I
don't I shouldn't have done that because
it it always just like let me verify
that, you know. Um
don't worry oh don't worry about using
the agent browser skill to verify
things. Just run it. I'll test if it
works. Right. We're gonna we're going to
do that for um we're going to steer
that.
Got our message queued up. Let's send it
now. Do some steering. Let's see how
we're doing on the HTML and canvas.
Don't consider to fall back to things
that are not HTML canvas is such a a
cool API to do this type of thing. Let's
go back to our explode. By the way, um
if you want to grab the code for this,
you go to github.combossexlode
or exploding and uh you can grab the
latest code. I'll push this up at the
end of this live stream.
Let's see what the chat's saying here.
Find the cure for cancer. West boss.
West boss is the goat. Prototype the
iPhone. Trifold. Oh, trifold.
Should we do that? Should we add more
folds? How many folds can we possibly
add to this type of thing?
All right. Nolan grid is ripping. You'll
see why.
This is why I'm really excited for the
like um Hydro Fusion stuff you guys were
showing earlier because I want to use
the latest models for a lot of this
exciting stuff because it's really good
at doing 3D, but I I also want to use
some of the faster models for simple
things like um writing some some
JavaScript that a calculator app, right?
We don't need to be spending $40 to do
that type of thing.
All right. Replace uniform grid. Let's
take a look at Oh, baby. This looks
good. Let's take a Let's zoom in on it.
Look at how impressive this actually is
with these hinge things. You know what
is a weird thing.
Having trouble zooming in and out of it.
Maybe that's that's a feature we should
be adding.
Um, yeah, let's do that.
I'm having trouble panning around. I can
zoom in and out and pan around it in 3D
space. But if I want to use my middle
click button or hold space and drag up
and down so I can pan in on different
parts, I'm having issues with that. Fix
it.
Let that sucker go.
Pentafold chat. Quad fold.
How many possible folds can we add to
it?
Astra is going edits the software. Come
on, give me some
still going on there. Let's Let's take a
look at our zoom thing.
Let's
There we go. It's looking a little bit
better.
On the orbit control
run doom on it. That's actually a a
fantastic idea. I really like that.
All these different apps on it.
Explode.
All right, fix panning at both viewers.
All right, let's go to the exploding
view. Beautiful.
There we go. Now I can I can use my
middle click button. I'm zooming around
into it.
Zoom in. Let's get really close in on
these on the motherboard shots here.
dual cell power system. That is so sick.
I'm I'm curious if this is actually
what it looks like inside. I don't think
that they'd be putting capacitors on top
of on top of screws. Um the closer you
get, it's it's not as impressive. But if
you zoom out a little bit or look at
some of these pieces, right? And then
let's go and get the
let's try the hinge.
Beautiful
nulling grid. Let's go a little bit
closer.
All right, let's check in on the canvas
based apps that we're working on here.
Exercise calculator.
It's taking a little longer than I had
thought. Maybe I should have used a a
less powerful model. Um I prefer speed
in this case. I definitely should have
bumped it down to a different model.
Uh let's go back to the exploding view
here. Just start more agents while you
wait. Does here. Does anybody have that
problem where like yeah, you got six or
seven agents running at once and you're
you're running in between them uh trying
to focus on them. That's a a little bit
tricky. I I think I think I I I max out
about maybe three or four.
Simulate the gyro sensor when you rotate
it. So the screen image will rotate
according to the orbit. That's actually
not a bad idea, simulating a gy gyro
sensor.
Or what would be cool is if we could
view it on our phone or use our phone as
the actual gyro. So, take the data from
the phone, pipe it into here, and then
you could use this as a sort of like a
remote control. I promised Burke I
wouldn't do any crazy hardware stuff, so
I'm not going to do that to him. Um, but
we'll uh maybe he can he can start
adding that specific one. This is really
cool. All right. Um, you know what I
want is let's start customizing the
color of it, right? um add a color
picker for being able to customize
the color of the iPhone and also add the
ability to change the background to
several different wallpapers.
Oh, baby, this is looking good. Um
I think
I am running this on
different thing. What is the URL for
this work tree?
This is a separate session. Okay. Where
is
how do I how do I see the apps? Oh, apps
preview. Okay.
Here we go. Open up the calculator.
Okay. So, this is the app, right? It
seems to be working here. But how do I
see
where it is? How do I see it on the
actual device itself? Right.
Apps preview. Apps preview to run these
on use chrome canary draw canvas
element. I am I'm on edge but I have
that turned on. Okay, good. Uh let's ask
you here. How do I preview the
applications on the phone? I don't see
the UI to turn that on.
Should
the wallpaper changes based on the
screen or the background? Ooh,
background behind. No, iPhone screen
wallpaper. That's what I need. Thank
you.
I do have HTML canvas turned on. Do I
not? Let me open up my another browser
that has it turned on.
this up. Let's see.
Canvas draw. Oh, maybe they took it out.
No, I I tested this right before we came
on here. Let's open up another browser.
Um,
It seems to be
all right. We'll just tell it. I do have
those things turned on, but I'm not
seeing it. Perhaps you could open up an
agent browser that is headed so I can
see it
because it was showing us screenshots of
it working. Right. If we look at go back
and look at our thinking,
we got that working on
Oh.
Oh, it just opened up a browser for me.
There we go. Um,
just make sure I've got this
on screen. There we go. Okay, got our
calculator.
Uh oh. Beach balling. There we go. Okay.
Oh, baby. Okay. Now, the question is is
can I spin the device around and still
add 171 + 1?
It works. Amazing. Hold on.
It doesn't show the app on the front. So
maybe that's something that you guys can
fix. But now we have the
base for having apps working on this
thing, right? And you can spin it around
and and do it in in 3D.
Oh, that is really cool. I'm also
sharing my screen right now and it is
feeling a little laggy, but when I was
not sharing my screen, it was not it was
uh quite a bit buttery. 8 * 9.
All right,
that is cool. Can we explode it?
We can still explode the app. So, the
screen is still running
the application, but we can we can go
through the full 3D exploded view for
this. That is absolutely awesome. All
right, we got one minute left. I'm
wondering what we should add really
quickly. What would be really cool
is webcam. I don't know if we're going
to get that done in time. Um, let's
start a new, but let's go to a faster
model. Um, let's do soul. Okay.
Add a new app that is a notes app.
All right, we're gonna let that go. We
got 30 seconds. Come on.
A lot le The chat is saying a lot laggy.
Yes, this is the the problem with uh
trying to render 3D while you're you're
sharing your screen on a stream. Um, it
was significantly buttery before I
started sharing my screen. So, it
actually works pretty well. Um, you
break it down into all the pieces. It's
not that much, right? It's it Let's get
in here. You got one second. Ah. All
right. We are out of time. What I'm
doing is I'm going to be challenging
Burke and Pierce. Can you get a couple
more apps running on this thing? camera
using your actual webcam would be really
cool. Notes app.
Web browser. I don't know if you could
do web browser or not because it's an
iframe inside of HTML canvas. Probably
won't work, but make sure you flip this
flag on um in your browser and and pick
it up from here.
>> Dude, that was awesome. Where is this
repo at?
Uh, it's at westboss on github slpp
or exploding. Hold on, let me push up my
commits here and I'll uh give you the
latest.
>> I found it.
>> Yep, we're there.
>> Yes. All right.
>> All right. Thank you so much. We will do
our best here to So, what? You want a
camera app, you want a notes app, and
you wanted you want you want us to build
a web browser from scratch. And any
anything else? Seems pretty simple.
>> Maybe start with the notes app.
>> Okay.
>> Uh get that working. Um make sure that
you have the HTML and canvas flag turned
on in your browser so it will actually
render inside the fold. Okay.
>> Um and then notes app easy, right? And
then hard hard is like build
like a like like the photo the camera
app and you can actually take photos
with it.
>> Can actually take photos. Okay, we're on
it. Wes, thank you so much. We're going
to get right on that. Have a great day.
All right. Well, shoot.
>> Um All right. Sorry.
>> Can't say I was expecting that was where
we were going to start.
>> No, not at all. I was hoping for like a
a personal portfolio website or
>> fantastic
>> something quite easy.
>> Sure.
>> Uh okay. So
uh where do you want to start?
>> Uh well I was I was just trying to you
know start with cloning some stuff. Uh
that's always a good place to start. Um
>> I was doing the same thing.
>> So let's go ahead and do that. West
boss.
Um and what did he call it?
>> It's called exploding.
>> Exploding.
So, I think we can just get this thing
up and running.
>> Yeah, let's just like and there there
was a a browser flag that we needed to
also
>> it's the canvas.
>> Is this is this an edge cuz we're
Chromium based or do we have to go to go
and
>> No, we should we should be able to uh
>> Well, I Googled HTML canvas and see
nothing. So,
>> in settings, but it would be
>> it's in edge
settings. No, is it settings? No, it
would be experiments maybe.
>> Let's see.
Um,
>> this I, you know, it's kind of funny
like my biggest challenge is getting my
machine into the the right state to do
what I want to do, installing the right
tools. Once we get there, I think we're
flying. Um,
>> I just asked Luna, turning
how
>> um, can you run this? I'm going to try
it and the built-in canvas inside the
app. uh in the browser canvas and uh
>> edge settings system settings
system
performance system turn on use graphics
acceleration when available
that's already on for me. Restart it.
Okay, we should be good.
>> So what are your So you just have to
have that toggle enabled and it should
work.
>> It should.
>> Okay,
>> so I'm going to So it's npm install npm
rundev. Nothing changes. So, it's so
interesting that you like immediately
jump into the app and you're using the
terminal, right? Let's jump to Burke's
screen here. Um,
>> because my my approach is like I don't
even do that anymore. I just like run
the can you please run this
>> like I I have that is kind of where I'm
at with a lot of things. Like I've even
>> just ask the agent to run
>> just ask the agent to do it, right? I
don't even bother because because like
what what sort of Yeah. You don't even
know what command to run here, right? So
what's what's interesting is because so
we're getting the Microsoft proxy
redirect.
>> Ah
>> so now we have to work around this. Um
>> every developer's worst nightmare it uh
>> yeah so we're we're just like you folks
we have restrictions essentially the way
it works is that there's
>> how does it how does it work? They when
we try to install packages they redirect
to an internal thing that just makes
sure that it's safe. Y
>> so if it's a newer package it's not
there I think is what it's like a 7day
window. So we have to see if we can
resolve this and work around it. Man, we
hit a a wall right out of the gate.
Thanks Wes.
>> Nothing relating to the actual project
itself.
>> I don't know what this package is. This
3106.
>> Well, he was saying he was using 3JS. So
some sort of 3JS related. It should be
there.
>> It should be. Yeah, we'll see if Luna
can I'm actually I should have probably
should have
>> picked a bigger model for this, but
>> I'm going to go and I'm going to use
Let's just like max out. I'm going to
use What should I use?
>> Let's go to Astra.
>> Astra, right? Um and I'm going to go
ahead and run that. Um so
just do it. Um and I'm going to go into
autopilot. I was already in approval.
Just go ahead and get this running. And
while this is happening, I also just
kind of want to explore what this thing
is.
>> It's a vap.
Um,
what is in package.json.
>> So, yeah, it's three. It's 3JS. Um,
>> I bet it's just
>> TypeScript and V. That's it.
>> I think it's probably just the version
of 3JS. We're just going to have to go
back a version.
>> Yep.
>> Um, Astra's on the on the job. Don't you
worry about it.
Um, so you know, speaking of models,
like what do you what is your model that
you tend to cook with these days? I know
it changes like every week we have a new
thing that has been launched into the
ether that changes how we work. And so,
you know, how are you thinking about all
these models and what you use?
>> Yeah. Oh man,
I mean,
I've been a big fan of Opus for a very
long time, you know, since four or five.
But when the Soul models came out or the
Yeah. Soul Luna Terra the 56 models uh
because Luna is so cheap. I mean it's
just it's almost free. I do a lot of
Luna on Macs.
>> Yep.
>> And it can actually do a lot. Um
and one of the things that we talk we've
talked about before is that working at
Microsoft we have unlimited
>> tokens. So we don't really live in the
real world.
>> Uh and so when you have that then if you
have a model like Fable which is an
amazing model.
>> Yeah. Right. Then then I would use
Fable. But then recently we have Astra.
I've been using a lot of Astra and then
we've got the new Hydra Fusion. I mean
Yep.
>> I mean I bounce around so much. I don't
know what what would you say your go-to
is?
>> I mean generally like latest open AI
latest anthropic variant and then I
always have like a fast model in my back
pocket for like like Wes was doing some
back and forth interaction and oh look I
got it running.
>> What' you do? Browser canvas. I just
said run the thing. I'm telling you,
man. Get out of the terminal. Just tell
you tell the agent what you want. I want
this to run in the browser uh inside of
the GitHub copilot app.
>> I've got it running, too. I've got it
running, too.
>> Okay. All right. There we go. Um I don't
know like I like using I like a Astra a
lot. I that's probably my daily driver.
I I have been using more Hydrofusion and
uh James kind of mentioned it in the
keynote, but we also we got a lot of
feedback about auto mode. Right. Right.
um mostly that it needs to be better.
And so the team did a really like
awesome job taking all that feedback
that you have given us and uh we're
rolling out a new auto in the coming
days. Um and so basically I already kind
of like teased that in the picker here.
You can click auto and then you can
optimize for um you know you can say do
I want to optimize for cost because I'm
in a token constrained environment. Do I
just want the best possible result? Uh
do I kind of want a mix of both? And you
can kind of change the knobs to be
exactly what you want. Yeah, Burke's
showing it on his screen here. Um, which
like before it was just kind of, you
know, efficiency mode essentially. And
so now we have more toggles so that you
don't have to like big brain what model
do I use for this task, right?
>> Our RML team has literally went and
built like custom routing models behind
the scenes to power this experience to
hopefully give you the best model for a
task. And then now with things like
hydrofusion like uh Julia showed us
earlier like you have to think even less
right because then hydrofusion is going
to give you like the best result way
less cost right I don't have to think
about all the models that are happening
every week all the you know what what
what does this benchmark say what does
that benchmark say do I use this for
that is it bad at this is it bad at that
right it just hurts your brain man
>> it does and then you feel like you're
ripping yourself off if you use the
wrong model because either you use too
much intelligence and you're overpaying
or you don't use enough and then you've
wasted a bunch of tokens because you end
up going to the higher intelligence.
>> That's that's correct. And like
actually, you know, I work a lot with
our team at Microsoft, which we have
80,000 plus engineers here and the the
interesting thing is you dig through the
data is most engineers will pick a model
and they just sit on that model for
everything, right? And even if you're
optimizing for intelligence, that can be
frustrating, right? Like if you're if
you're running fable fable maxing all
day, that model's going to take some
time. So if you're doing something where
you want like fast interaction feedback
loop, even if in theory you have
unlimited tokens, that that may not be
the right model, right, for that
particular situation. And so given that
we saw at Microsoft we have 80,000
engineers, they're not they're just
picking one model and sticking on it.
And that may not they may be good or
maybe bad, right? Um like that was what
led us to create things like auto and
hydrofusion because we were experiencing
this problem for ourselves.
Yeah. And I think I mean again because
we have unlimited tokens I do tend to
pick like I'll just pick Astra and hang
out there, right? It's like stage and
commit. Astraax.
>> Yep.
>> So, but but most people most folks just
can't do that. I It would be nice if we
could get to a world though where
everyone gets that level of intelligence
all the time. Super cheap, super fast.
All right. I've added
a not Didn't he say add a notes app? It
said it already has a notes app. The
simulator already includes a notes app.
All right. Well, how do you open it up
then phone?
>> Full screen this puppy. You can full
screen the canvas. Nope, not that
button. The one next to it.
>> This one right here. Okay. So, it says
go to apps
notes. Oh, because he added it. That was
the last thing he did and then it must
have got pushed. Okay, so there already
is one.
>> So, we have we have a notes app. It's,
by the way, it is crazy that he's just
like, I'm gonna add, you know, apps to
this thing, and it it not only is
functional, but also looks exactly like
the notes app.
>> It does.
>> He just did that in 20 minutes. That's
insane.
>> I need to I wish I could decrease my
There we go. There we go.
>> Sorry, I bumped up your font like
ridiculously when you were not
>> when I was gone. Okay, so we have a
notes app. Um, and so Okay, so we've
already done Well, he did that.
>> He did that.
>> So, now we need to add a camera. He said
add a camera app.
So, let's
let's go back here. So, let's do this.
>> What do you think I should do? If you're
going to add camera, you know,
>> I think you should do the web browser.
>> Okay.
Just no no small task. Let's let's
bundle up some Chromium in this thing.
>> Yeah. How hard could it be? All right.
And then uh we'll put like a AAA game on
here at some point. Um
>> Doom naturally. add a camera app to this
phone simulator that uses the hardware
camera here on my laptop. We'll be fine.
And we need to be able to save photos.
So, while you're at it, I guess just go
ahead and add a photos app, too.
It can't be that easy. Just just ask.
Now, we should point out I'm using Astra
here. I'm not do I'm not using any sort
of skills or MCP servers or anything.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm not planning. Yeah,
>> I'm just we're just yoloing.
>> We we were talking about I mean it
certainly depends what sort of project
you're working on, right? Um but like we
were I saw your tweet the other day and
you were like I don't really actually
plan that much anymore as an explicit
thing.
>> Correct. With
>> Why is that the case? Do you think the
models are just in good enough shape?
>> Because they because they give me what I
want. So they're so intelligent like
>> Chad if you hired a senior dev right
somebody who was really expensive a
really good person you would expect not
to have to tell them every single thing
that they have to do you would just
point them in the right direction and
these newer models in my opinion are
very much in that vein right and
actually I feel like if I over plan
actually get a worse result it's better
to let the model actually fill in and be
like well I did this here and then I'll
be like wow what
>> I didn't think to do that but I wish I
I think I've been there for a couple
generations too um of models where
maybe since like 55 GBD 55 and
definitely with 56 I found myself doing
a lot less of that and like I would say
I in a weird way I actually still plan
but it was it's more of like an
interactive thing. I'm like, "Hey, you
know, I do what you did. I go to voice.
I'm like, "Okay, this is kind of roughly
the shape of what I want to do, how I
want it to work." Spire that off, right?
And then it's going to come back with
something, you know, that's kind of what
I want, but not and you're kind of going
back and forth a little bit. And so, I
will kind of stay in interactive mode,
not official plan mode, but I'll stay in
interactive mode in the GitHub Copot
app. And when I feel pretty good about
it, like then I'll just be like, "All
right, let's switch this puppy over into
autopilot. Go do your thing."
I've literally like if you have like a
very difficult task, some of the
projects we're working on in the copod
app now fall into this category. I will
it will literally run sometimes 3, four,
five, six hours. Oh yeah. Right. And I
just go to bed. I'll I'll make sure I
like I feel like I'm not maximizing my
time if I'm not like hey I need to give
this while you're sleeping
>> stuff while I'm sleeping which is maybe
like a interesting you know thing for us
to consider as society. But uh yeah like
I I that's basically how I work now. And
then I am like batching tasks, right?
Because you know I'm a PM, you're in
Devril, like we're jumping around
meetings, we got customer stuff, right?
And so like you're not always just
sitting staring at, you know, your
computer doing, you know, coding eight
hours a day anymore. So like I find
myself trying to batch stuff together.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, where I'll be like, okay, I'm
going to kick off like five things.
Maybe I need to steer it a little bit at
the beginning and then it's just kind of
I'll check back in on this later. And
also I found like cognitively that's
easier for me as well because then
you're not in the like constant I need
to be managing 15 threads and like you
can do the parallel work but like in
terms of how you're actually approaching
reviewing it. You're jumping back in and
actually reviewing each synchronously.
>> All right. So what's happening here? Are
you already done?
>> Yeah, it's already ready. So
>> there is no way, dude. All right, let's
see.
>> This camera is off. Enable camera.
Waiting for
>> Oh my goodness. This is This is gonna be
Wait for it.
>> Oh my gosh.
Oh, selfie.
Hold on. Okay. Did it go to the photos
app? Let's go to photos. Uh, home
photos. There's no photos. Zero photos
were saved. Okay.
>> Okay. So, but it's still pretty good for
first prompt, right?
>> Not bad. Okay. So, uh, what now? What
are you doing? Uh I was I actually was
kind of sending a you know a prompt just
a second ago. I was just like how does
this thing even work right? Uh because
this is not a codebase I'm familiar
with. So I was just kind of trying to
understand at a high level how like this
is rendered how the apps work inside the
phone. Um there's a shell ts there's a
software.ts, right? Um, and so I'm
mostly just trying to have some
semblance of understanding of the
architecture of this thing considering
in theory I'm giving it a very difficult
task to go out a web browser to this
thing. Um,
>> so are you doing planning?
>> No, you're just going to go straight in.
>> Yeah, I'm just I'm just straight going
in. Um,
and like the interesting thing with this
sort of task like this is a very
exploratory prototyping task. So I would
say like in a real project like when I
work on the GitHub copilot app something
I might do is like we build so many
throwaway prototypes and like in a weird
way the prototype is your plan right and
then once you're like okay I need to do
this for real Z's and this needs to be
production code that's well tested
that's well architected that's
performant then what you can ask the
agent to do is basically hey look at my
branch for this prototype extract the
essence of what I want let's figure out
how to do this the right way quote
unquote and then we ship the
But then you give yourself the freedom
to explore with the prototype where
where you don't have to actually worry
about those things. You just prove it
works.
>> Yeah. No, I I I feel the exact same way
that I'm just working with output now
and working with outcome. What's
interesting here is that so I told the
agent I was like the photos aren't
saving and it's now driving the canvas.
It's trying to take pictures and test.
Oh, it says it's fixed.
Well, there's still no photos there.
Let's see.
Enable camera.
Okay, let's go back home. Photos. There
they are. Okay, so the camera app is
working. That was way too easy. Need
some more challenges here. All right,
let's see what you're working.
>> It's funny how we kick this off by being
like, "The last challenge was too easy."
And Wes is like, "Hey, I built an
emulator for this thing. Can you add
more apps to it?" And by one prompt, you
managed to do it.
>> All right. Uh chat, you're going to So,
let's see what PICE is doing. I'm going
to go over check with chat and then
we'll I think we're going to need some
help from chat here just to actually
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> give us ideas.
>> Yeah, give us ideas. We need your ideas.
>> Um
let's see. Um what else do what else can
we do here? Um
>> let me mute this here.
All right, chat. Let's see.
I'm looking at chat. Chat, get your
ideas in. What apps should we add here?
>> I'm adding a GitHub app. Um, because I
feel like that's necessary for this
experience. Like this thing was made to
run my agents, man. So, I want to see if
I can get my agents running on this
thing. Copilot SDK, everything. Let's
like actually turn it into a form factor
where I'm kicking off agents on this
simulator.
>> It's actually running on the device.
Yes. Okay. Yes. And then uh so like uh
No, I'm going to use voice. Hey. Um, so
I basically want to turn this device
into a way that I manage my coding
agents with GitHub Copilot. We have the
GitHub Copilot SDK. I essentially want
to have a control plane for my agents in
this uh in this simulator, be able to
kick things off. We should use all the
awesome features that are available in
this device. It has multiple folds. It
has a front, a back. We should figure
out some really cool interaction
patterns that make it super awesome to
partner with agents inside of this
simulator. So, let's go explore that
with the GitHub copilot SDK.
Cool. Also, I'm realizing like we're
going to end up are we going to all end
up in phone boost because you're trying
I I'm like I need to wait for Burke to
finish talking to his agent so I can
talk to my agent real quick right here.
>> Oh, with the voice. I'll Yeah, I'm
timing. So Wes said Wes said he said um
spin up 50 sub aents to replicate all
the apps on the iPhone. Do it.
>> That's what I did.
>> Uh let's see what should all app Okay.
So the interesting like I don't know if
if this is co-pilot um app doing this or
Astra doing this but even when I'm not
in plan mode it still will ask me
questions
>> that it is because the agent is given an
ask question tool. And I I think like
some of it is the model right? So like
the harness does give the model the tool
but the model has to decide I actually
want to go back to the user right and so
I do think Astra has like a tendency
especially the beginning of something
like this to really try and clarify your
requirements. Uh, okay. So, built-in
iPhone apps with browser compatibility
compatible functionality. Built-in apps
plus optional Apple apps such as pages,
numbers, and GarageBand, which should
>> I recommend
>> GarageBand in this puppy. That's going
to be
>> clearly labeled simulations where so
iCloud, Apple Pay, native hardware, and
APIs aren't available. We're just gonna
go all in, man. Why not?
Okay. And uh
you're gonna kill me. But uh
I used the restroom right before this
thing started and I have to use
>> Okay, that's cool.
>> I'll be right back. You drive chat. I'll
be right back.
>> Let's go full screen.
>> Too much Coke Zero.
>> Uh Coke Zeroed up. Hey, can you give me
a drink while you're at it?
>> Like a lemonade or something? Um, so, so
while Burke was talking, what I've done
here is, you know, one of the things I
love about the GitHub copilot app is I
can very easily fire off multiple tasks
at the same time. So, of course, we
started over here and this was our
Chromium uh, experiment. And so, that's
gone ahead and that's running in one
thing. But, as you're giving us more
ideas in chat, I'm going and firing
these things off. I'm actually when
Burke gets back I'm gonna have him pull
back up the chat and I'll kick off three
or four ideas based off what we've seen
in the chat. But you can see I'm running
three agents here at the same time. And
basically how this works in the GitHub
copilot app is each session by default
when I go this new session thing you can
see I have I have several options here
right I have new work tree local
repository and cloud. So new workree is
basically creating a branch of this
exploding uh repo in a separate folder
and so my agents will not collide as
they work. That is the default inside
the GitHub copilot app because it's
built for parallel work moving multiple
tasks forward at once. And so that's
that's our default here. But of course I
can also just run it against like
whatever directory or sorry whatever
branch I have checked out for this app.
So I could pick local repository. So I
will often do this for you know other
things that I'm using the GitHub copilot
app for like you know quering telemetry
building presentations where you know
it's helpful to have the repo scope and
all the skills and things like that that
are in the repo but I'm not really
making code changes. I'm not worried
about collisions and so I want to pick
that. We also have this cloud option and
that's actually going to kick this task
off to the cloud agent. I can of course
steer it and see what's going on
entirely from uh entirely from the
GitHub copod app. So once we get some of
those ideas, I may kick off a couple
cloud tasks in addition to the ones I
have locally. Um, we're actually working
a lot on kind of this remote agent
paradigm
because I think you'll find like
separate from the ability to run things
locally like you will quickly run into
device constraints, right? And it's not
so much from the agent itself, it's that
our agents are now going they're
obviously building the thing that we're
working on. In the case of GitHub
copilot app, that's Rust, right? So try
to try to fire up several Rust builds.
You're going to run into trouble on even
a very OP machine. Um so you're going to
run into problems there. Uh then also
verification, right? Uh Wes was showing
us like how he does some agentic
verification. But if you're not only
just building the app, you're running
each of these in their own work tree.
It's going it's booting the app. It's
running through a ton of tasks. It's
driving the UI. Those are very compute
intensive on your machine. And so you'll
eventually get to the point that like
you will be forced to push these things
onto a remote workspace. And so there's
a lot of work going on that we're
excited to show you at GitHub Universe
uh next month in terms of like how this
remote agent stuff works. You you know
you could use a dev box, you could use
um you know a code space, you could use
an Azure VM, you could use any arbitrary
remote to basically set up uh a place
where you want these remote agents to
run. And of course then once you do
that, any GitHub co-pilot client could
in theory, you know, talk to that thing.
So you could start something in the
GitHub mobile app, pick it up in the
GitHub desktop app. So there's all kinds
of fun stuff that's possible. And so I'm
super excited about kind of this remote
execution thing and getting more things
off of my machine. Um, so yeah, let's
check in on what some of these things
are doing.
So um, it looks like it's going through
and adding some of the Chromium stuff.
Uh, I can also come in here and you can
see like in the GitHub copod app, this
thing is firing off like a ton of sub
aents and things like that. So, here's
one that's running around implementing
the Chromium back in. Here's one that is
actually going and building something.
Uh, what else do we have going on? Um,
if I jump over to which one was this?
The GitHub app. It's going ahead and
adding that. Now, I asked it to do the
real GitHub app. It did ask me a
question about that. I was like, "No, I
don't want mock data. I want you to
actually talk to GitHub. For now, this
is going to use the GH CLI and the O
token from that to kind of query the
data so I don't have to go and, you
know, set up OOTH and all that fun stuff
for the simulator, which I think is a
reasonable choice. Um, and then let's
check in on this one I had around using
the GitHub Copod SDK. And one thing
maybe Burke and I didn't like go super
into is you can see like we used to be
so particular about our prompts, right?
It was like, oh, I need to um, you know,
prompt in this very specific way. I need
to avoid any contradictions. I need to
uh be very precise in basically how I'm
partnering with with the models. And I
think as the capability has increased
increasingly, right, like doing
something like I'm just going to word
vomit my prompt into thank you into the
GitHub copilot app. The model is capable
to the point that you don't have to have
like the most perfect well-crafted
prompt anymore. You can just talk to
this thing and things will happen. Oh
man, I see Burke. Let's jump over to
Burke. He's got he's got sub agents
going. He's got me eliminated.
>> We've got
>> What's happening?
>> Yeah. So, we have So, this session
didn't spawn a
iMovie Garage Band.
Oh, my mic. Helps if I turn my mic on.
So, this session right here spawned all
of these, one for each app. So, we have
an in iMovie.
>> Okay.
>> GarageBand, Keynote, Free Form, Measure,
Numbers, Pages, Journal, Stocks,
FaceTime.
>> Dude, FaceTime is going to be crazy if
we can get that working.
>> Magnifier, passwords, find my
There's no way all this stuff's going to
actually work, though.
>> I'm a bit worried your machine may
explode during the the course of this
live stream here.
>> TV app, reminders, podcast. Some of
these are already done. Files is done.
Settings is done.
>> Wait,
>> app store is done. How can the app store
be done?
>> Let's go into the app store. I want to
see what what what the model has cooked
up for this.
>> Well, they're not there.
>> Oh, because they're different work
trees. It's going to have to get it back
into
>> um Oh, how is what is the best way to do
this? So, each one of these is a work
tree.
>> Yes.
>> Which means my hard drive is is also
maxed out.
>> So, each one of these work tree. How do
we get it back to test in the main
session? I could have it merge each work
tree back.
>> Yeah. So, basically in this in this main
one, you can so the GitHub copilot app
can control the GitHub copot app. So,
you could say something like when you're
done, bring it back, bring it back to
this session and and so basically then
what the GitHub copot app will do, it's
given tools that can create sessions
like it did here. It can also monitor
those sessions. And so when it monitors
and it's done, the sub agent can send a
message back to this and say I'm done,
it will say message received. And then
this agent will actually go and
integrate the changes. So that's totally
something the app can do on its own. You
just got to ask.
>> So let's see here. Yeah, I did it right
here. When you're done, bring the apps
back here and into this work tree. So it
should merge them back.
Actually, I want to say as the apps
finish, let's see here.
Let's copy this
as the apps finish. As that's one S, not
it's not two S's on on as as the apps.
As the apps finish, bring them back and
merge into this work tree here. Uh,
yeah, perfect. There we go.
All right.
>> All right. What do you know?
>> How do you How do you get into the apps
again?
>> Uh, it's right. It's below the preview.
There's an apps preview. It's like teeny
tiny. There you go. Yeah.
>> All right.
>> The browser.
>> Let's try. Okay. I can't click in. So,
not great. Chromium companion is not
running. Okay. So, we're, you know,
we're making some progress. I don't know
why it built two
pains here.
>> Uh, because it's a foldable phone, so
the UI is different. I would have to
totally rethink how I want to.
>> Yeah,
>> that's a bit weird. So then should we
render like
>> the above the fold on the left and the
below the fold on the like now I have
two folds.
>> How what should I do in terms of like
maximizing the surface area?
>> Should you like have the page continue
on the right hand side?
>> That's what I'm wondering. Or is that
like just wasteful and like
I don't know that I actually want that
as a user but then I feel
>> because then if you're scrolling that's
just going to be weird. It's going to
scroll from one side to the other side.
Or it could work. That actually could
work,
>> dude.
>> I mean, you'd have to see it work in
order.
>> We're going to have to try it. I think
that's going to hurt my brain a little
bit. I got to be honest. Um, it's always
fun when these new form factors come out
because you have to kind of rethink how
you actually build software for it. Um,
all right. What's going on with our
build build browser compon uh companion
here?
Okay.
I am still going here cranking away on
the home app. app, the Shortcuts app,
the books app, the numbers app, numbers.
It's going to create a spreadsheet
app just on the fly.
>> Time to be alive, man.
>> It is. It is actually It's super fun.
You can literally I really do believe
like our our limit is now like our
creativity. And that's like a very
cliche like handwavy thing to say, but
like the fact that all you're seeing all
this come to life like people who are
just extremely ambitious and creative
are going to do really well in this new
world. I really believe that.
>> Yeah. And it's I mean it's uh it's so
because I was thinking about this before
like the grill me skill from Matt really
changed everything. And the thing about
it is it's really simple. I think it's
like he said it's like four sentences.
I've never actually looked at it but
it's really simple. It's just an idea
and the idea is to just have the agent
>> persistently ask you questions
>> and that just works, right? So like it's
these simple ideas. I think now
>> Yep.
>> have a lot of impact. Yep.
>> Right.
>> Yeah. I I mean
>> who has maybe maybe the idea guys it is
the era of the idea of the idea guy.
>> Um
>> Yeah. No, that's that's it's very
interesting. Yeah. Like the the skill
thing also reminds me like I was talking
about it while you were gone. Like I
remember I I do a lot of like you know
meet and greets with different
developers seeing how they work and I
learned a ton of cool stuff. But like
one thing that like I see that I think
is kind of an anti-attern is
increasingly I see people basically like
I need to spend you know a month
perfectly optimizing my agentic system
with all these skills and MCP servers
and you're like yeah but what are you
doing and like then it's actually kind
of hard for people to explain like what
that all does. But I think the like the
Matt PCO like skill is like such a great
example. It's like you don't have to
have this like you know 50,000line
markdown file of here is how our team
works and everything.
>> You can now now these models are so
capable you it's more about
communicating your intent and you don't
have to do that in a lot of words. Yeah.
>> Just takes a couple
>> and especially these newer models
they're so good. I mean in the past you
had to give the model these guard rails
but I feel like now
>> the more guardrails I give it the more
I'm like inflicting my own
>> errors. Your own limiting you're
limiting beliefs. you're limiting the
communicating to the agent, right?
>> And it's it's kind of
>> but in a weird way, it's like and like a
lot of things that were like uh
anti-atterns for software engineering
are now like perhaps how you should
work, right? Like constraint has always
been good when building software.
>> Yeah.
>> And in a way, like to your point, the
model when you actually give it an
underspecified plan if you're in the
prototyping stage in a kind of
interesting way, it has creativity
because these things are
non-deterministic. And so if you spend
five of these things, you're going to
get five different results. And like in
a weird way, having an oversp specified
plan of you have to work exactly in this
way, you're not allowing the model to
really express its like
>> it's non-determinism on the solution,
right?
>> Yeah. You're limiting the
>> people are going to like this. You're
limiting the better developer in the
conversation
to your
>> Well, it's it's it's the way I view it
is kind of like a team, right? you know,
um, yes, like some ideas are better than
others, but like on a team, everyone
brings a different perspective and that
makes the thing you're building better.
And so it's just kind of natural when
partnering with agents, especially using
different models, like if you prototype
the thing three or four times with three
or four different models, you're getting
different perspectives, right? And it is
true that if you oversp specify your
plan, then you're reducing the
creativity because you're adding
constraint, right?
>> 100%.
>> So it's a feature and a bug.
>> Uh, let's see. Can we bring my screen
up, Matt, if you could, so we can see.
Oh, no. Just as I do that, my it goes
away. It was here. We had some apps.
>> I saw them.
>> The agent's cooking again.
>> I I hear like the mic is his mic is
right here, but like the fan I hear this
thing going.
>> Oh, man. It is
>> It's going to get hot in here. We still
got an hour to go.
>> It's going to be like Florida by the
time we get out of here.
Oh yeah, this thing is struggling.
>> Well, while you were gone, I was talking
about like how I feel like if you can do
things like what you just did, your
local machine becomes the constraint,
right? Because it's not even just you're
running 50 agents is that each agent is
building, compiling, running your app,
validating it works.
>> Yeah. Look at this. Look at all these
agents running. Look at this,
>> dude. There's so many. And the thing is
like this is an M5 Mac Pro.
>> Top of the line. I I I buy I buy my own
hardware because I want access to the
best and like same thing like I'm
running top-of-the-line everything at my
house. I have top-of-the-line Mac Studio
and even that, you know, unified memory
and everything. You're pushing the
boundary of what that thing can do.
>> I know it. Well, um I wonder
got a blank page here. Trying the
browser.
Let's see here. Burke, enable the HTML
in canvas flag on your browser. I don't
know where that is.
>> Someone's going to have to in the in
chat. Can someone figure out in Edge
settings how we do that?
>> Yeah.
>> Or we can go install Chrome if we need
to. But
>> how?
>> Look, I How do I enable I
enable the
>> I told you this is going to be the
hardest part.
>> Flag in Edge, please.
>> Just have Luna do it.
>> I I have something I'm not supposed to
show, but I'm gonna, you know, we like
to have fun here. We're amongst friends
on the stream and um
>> what do you got?
>> I it was already up so I'm not revealing
something that wasn't already up but
like there speaking of new things in the
pipeline um if I jump over here look at
look at these tool calls. H
>> oh
>> that that would be great if GitHub
copilot had that feature wouldn't it? Um
so always new things cooking things on
the horizon uh from the GitHub copilot
team. So, I did have streamer mode on,
so I wasn't expecting that that would be
hidden, but here we are. So, always a
fun nugget for folks on the stream. Um,
you know what's interesting is like I'm
realizing that like despite running
three things, like you're more
aggressive strategy of I'm going to do
50 sub agents is probably actually more
likely to produce like a demoable result
than what I'm doing.
>> I really believe that.
>> You think so? Yes, I do.
>> All right, hold on. If it says in Edge
can No, we already did this. I opened
Edge literally. Yeah, I don't I don't
actually see it. HTML in canvas. Maybe
we need I need
>> just install Chrome. We'll give it a go.
>> Edge. Maybe I need Edge Canary.
>> Don't know if it if it is a new like
Chromium thing, then yeah, like I could
see that being a deal.
>> What do I need? Where is this? Where
>> we don't know how we don't know how
things work? I'm building a browser, but
I don't know what I need to do.
>> Edge Canary. Edge Canary.
>> Um,
>> pull it in. We'll try Canary. That
doesn't work.
So, you know, one other thing that the
is really powerful with these agents
that I'm seeing on my screen right now
is um
you know, not only are, you know, is
GitHub copilot going and writing the
code and making sure it compiles and all
that, but like we also saw it in Wes's
demo, like it's going and actually like
running the thing, basically creating
its own acceptance tests, like using
feedback loops, like you know, in this
case, screenshots to say, does it do the
thing? That saves me so much time
because I remember like I call like AI
1.0 0 era like with partnering with
agents like most of your time was like
all right like you know mpm install n
mpm rundev like all right let's boot
this up and then you like click through
and you're like you didn't even do the
most basic thing and then you're like
all right back to the drawing board you
prompt this now you're to you totally if
you do not want to be part of that
initial just basic validation loop you
do not have to be
>> which is super because we have this
shared thing right here
>> in the GitHub copilot app and we also
have this in VS Code um the built-in
browser in our tool tools uh basically
uh exposes tools back to the agent so
that uh it can do things like navigate,
take screenshots, click elements, right?
Um if you shared your browser session
with the agent, which in this case I
have inside the GitHub copilot app. And
so that's like a super powerful unlock.
But it does make me wonder like of
course there's things like computer use
on the horizon, but it does make it's
like yet another reason the web stack I
think is winning because like it just
like all of these things are already
there. the building blocks you need for
your agent. You don't have to go build
anything.
>> Yeah.
>> Like I don't this is already just like
building on you the shoulders of giants
of things that have happened in web tech
over the past 15 years, right?
>> Yeah, I totally agree. I mean
>> and then other stacks that are less
agent accessible like for this sort of
thing are going to struggle. I really
believe that.
>> But I'm trying to install Edge Canary at
the moment. Hold on. I can't multitask.
Edge Canary. Here we go.
>> Makes me nervous installing
I drug it in. Uh
>> okay. So, uh the other thing that I also
aggressively have my agents do is you
know rubber duck.
>> So, like basically second opinion with a
a model from a different family. I'm
using Astra might use Opus or something
like that. Um
I pretty aggressively prompt as part of
this like I don't like when I fire
something off I want you to self-
validate but I also always ask it to do
adversarial code review. always because
that I found myself doing this thing
where I would jump back into my session
and I'm like I don't want to embarrass
myself sending this PR to the team. I
need to rubber duck this thing right
quick even though
>> before somebody is like hey
>> before someone you know a real quote is
like yeah like your slop is gonna mess
up our codebase I need to run a rubber
duck real quick but if you find yourself
just constantly being like all right I
need to run this command
>> like that's the moment in time when
you're like this thing does actually
have to become part of my workflow as an
instruction right so I actually have
like literally at the end of every turn
I want you to run a rubber duck now that
does reduce the interactivity
because I'm adding additional length to
the turn, but it also means that I'm
getting like I'm basically saving myself
having to come in and manually hit enter
on that prompt.
>> Yeah,
>> it's just going to happen.
>> I don't think this is I don't Oh, it's
trying to install all of my extensions.
I don't think this is actually in Edge.
All right. Um,
Chrome
Wes forcing me forcing me to download
browsers that I don't want. I have a
browser.
>> It makes me really I I must say it does
make me really nervous installing
software live on a live stream.
>> I mean, what could go wrong?
>> I I will say, you know, Megan demoed the
Slack integration earlier, which is
super cool. Um,
that thing is always fun demoing. like I
had a customer demo showing that thing
off last week and you're like I probably
shouldn't show my Slack but I'm going to
show my Slack. Uh because you know it it
demos best in your actual work
environment, right?
>> Yeah, that's the thing is you got to
show you have to
>> if you don't have all the context of how
you're normally working then it it's
kind of a little contrived, right? So
you kind of need it to be real.
>> I mean I'm always somewhat terrified
whenever I'm demoing anything. But you
and you and me both kind of like to live
on the edge, which I think makes pe you
know, the very polished people at our
our company who like very well manicured
messages nervous, but like we we just
like to keep it real here.
>> That's that's that's all we've got.
>> Yeah,
>> that's all we've got. All right, we're
going to try this browser. Let me go
back over to YouTube and see if we've
got chat can help us out here. Feel like
chat knows how to fix this.
>> All right, hold on. It's saying my
GitHub simulator might be ready. So,
we're gonna
>> Okay, I have to connect to GitHub cohot
CLI.
>> Look at this. We got a GitHub app. All
right. So, here's his What is this?
Okay, these are my These are my repos.
I'm a little nervous to click into
these. Um,
there's the GitHub monolith. Yeah. Um,
some of these are private repos. Let's
go to a public repo. Um,
what is a good public repo? I wanted the
West Boss one. Can I go to that?
No. So, the search isn't working great
here.
>> Yeah. So, we're seeing the chat now.
Sorry. Sorry, chat. Where requires
browser restart.
Which browser?
Edge Canary.
>> Okay.
>> I just I just installed.
>> Look at this. I We have a somewhat
working GitHub app. Look at this, dude.
We got We got this. It's using my my O
token from, you know, the GitHub CLI and
populating data via that. And we have a
little foldable here. I need to once I
get my my co-pilot agent integration in
this puppy, I want to be able to like
fire this off as a as a something,
right, for the like one of these issues,
I should be able to just like in the
GitHub copilot app be like new session
from this issue.
>> Okay. Um, I actually, you know, now that
I'm thinking about it, I kind of just
want it to port the GitHub copilot app
into into this simulator.
>> Just like point it at the GitHub copilot
app.
>> Yeah. Give it the repo and say literally
port port this to the to the simulator.
>> I mean, why not? I'm still trying.
>> We have a rust rust backend uh with Tori
and then we have a front end that's like
typical web stack.
>> Is that known?
>> Yep. We talk
>> architecture is known. Yeah. Yeah.
>> I mean, so like that is a very
interesting thing with uh
>> I'm getting yelled at in the chat. All
right.
>> What are you getting yelled at about?
>> Uh because I keep trying to do it in
Edge and Wes is like it's people are
like it's in Edge. It's been there for a
long time. Wes is like it's not on Edge.
In all caps. All right.
We're gonna make it. Hold on.
>> We're doing our best here.
So, I'm also interested in what's going
on here. I'm
>> finally reach out. I'm doing the best I
can. I'm not the best multitasker.
Oh my gosh. Stay signed out, please.
Just just just I just want to run the
thing.
>> I got to see what kind of code we're
working with here. I need to look under
the hood. I'm in VS Code.
>> Oh, my computer's just barely running.
>> I like literally It's getting hot in
here.
>> There it is. It's right there. Okay.
>> It was lit. Wait, it was itch. Oh, this
Chrome.
>> No, this is Chrome. So, relaunch. All
right. Any Chrome. I got it. I got it.
Thank you, Wes. Um, I
>> feel like Wes is yelling at me. Um,
okay. Now,
now, now, now. Where did it go?
So, let's grab this here. What? I don't
understand what I need this for. It was
working just fine.
>> What? I think it it I don't know. Wes
can tell us in the chat the specific
purpose.
>> I think we weren't getting full 3D
rendering.
>> Is that what it is?
>> But I'm not sure.
>> Look at that.
>> Looks pretty.
>> That's actually pretty smooth.
>> We turn on hiding in this dock here.
>> Um, turn hiding on.
>> Perfect. All right.
>> Full screen that puppy.
>> Boom.
Um. All right. So, there we go for 3D.
Scroll down here to our little bit of
cheese here to the apps.
App preview. Oh my gosh, we have so
many. We have books. We have a calendar.
The calendar works. Wait, when is this
thing come out? It's like October the
16th or something.
>> You know, I couldn't decide if I was
going to order one, but I think I am
now.
>> Are you?
>> No free ads. I think I am going to order
one.
>> Pre-order maybe.
Start event. Save event. We've got one.
>> Oh my goodness.
>> Okay, so that's calendar. Um, clips.
What is clips?
>> I have no idea. There's so many
pre-installed things now. I don't know
what they do.
>> Wait, the chat dialogue is killing me.
So, make the chat show on the phone. Oh,
okay. I like that idea. Um,
>> how I don't even know what to ask for
there. All right, hold on. Um, how would
how would I how would me this is
interesting because the chat is in
YouTube. So, let let me just do it like
this.
Yeah, I would do it like this.
We're doing a live stream and there is a
chat that I keep having to pop out. Um,
it's on the GitHub live stream. The
channel is youtube.com/github.
It's a live it's live right now. Can you
help me get that chat just here in this
application so we can have the chat in
the application with us instead of the
the popped out chat?
>> Wait, Burke, my let's let's swap over to
me. Wait, am I going to be able to No,
it's not going to show the comments.
>> Oh, no.
>> No, wait. Will it show the comments?
It's a little laggy. I'm not sure I'm in
love with this how we're rendering this,
by the way. Okay. Yeah, it's not going
to let me open. Do I have to sign in? Is
that why I can't open the live chat?
because my my Chromium browser has been
implemented now.
>> Yeah, you do need to sign in. Can't chat
if you're not signed in.
>> I'll do that real quick. Probably should
take my screen off the live stream, but
we have we have our Chromium browser
now. So, maybe I can actually be the
workaround for this because we have
Chromium working in this Duo simulator.
I still don't understand what we need
Chrome for. It works fine right here.
>> What are we doing? Why do I need that?
All right. What else do we have? We have
the compass.
>> Is it Is it actually compassing?
>> There's like a manual.
>> Well, there's a browser API for Compass,
isn't there, chat? There's a browser API
for Compass.
>> Let me see here.
Um,
I did, didn't I restart Chrome? I did.
It asked me.
I don't understand,
Wes. I don't understand what's supposed
to be working that's not working. It
looks like it's working to me.
The split screen. What?
Let's bring it back up. HTML canvas
remembers the apps on the 3D model. Oh,
is that that's how it's supposed to
work? Like they're it's supposed to
render here.
>> Uh yeah, I think that's what he's
saying. Like it
>> Oh, so you can see them.
>> So wait, so pull up one of these apps. I
want to I want to see this.
>> Well, which app? How do I pull up an
app?
>> Wait, do you not have the app button
still? No.
>> Yeah, but then that takes us over here
to the preview.
>> That's But I saw Wes doing it. There has
to be. All right, Wes. Phone a friend
again. Wes, what do I do?
>> What do I do?
>> Wes was only supposed to be here for 20
minutes.
We We want those appear. Yes. Okay.
Showing apps on the device directly.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Okay. Perfect. Why is
that not working? It's right here,
man.
Now I don't know how to get back to the
device with the Chrome reset.
No display on off. On.
front rear perspective.
Refresh.
There we go. It's back. Um I don't know.
It's still trying to implement all these
freaking apps. So, I'm going to do this
one. Stop. Just stop. Stop and discard.
Okay. Get That's enough app. That's
enough apps, bro. Too many apps now.
>> Please stop. Uh, instead,
can you make sure that the apps render
on the 3D model? Uh, Wes said to turn on
the HTML in canvas, which I did,
but uh, I can't. I don't know. Okay. Um,
maybe chat's over here. Swipe.
Honestly, y'all, I have no clue. Like,
no, this just
>> No, because if you swipe, it's just
changing the
>> And there it's not showing here either.
I assume this is a schematic. That's not
even
build on a new point of view. D. It's
not over here, is it?
>> Uh,
>> no, no, no, no.
>> How can I run apps in the 3D mode, not
the app preview mode?
Uh,
Astra's on the case. Don't you worry
about it. The simulator tabs. Uh, Google
Chrome.
I'll stop adding apps and focus on the
3D display.
Oh, yeah. Computer use. It's gonna try
to It's going to look at my
It basically it just remember that what
was there was a skit. remember the old
skid chat where there was like a I don't
know maybe I'm dating myself here but
there's this old like tech support would
come in I think it was SNL and they'd be
the person would be sitting at the
computer like standing over their
shoulder you know and they'd be like
well like I'm trying to print and won't
print and he'd be like he'd go move
and then you know they move out of the
way he get in I feel like that's the
agent's like move
um so it's my agent is saying if you do
you see a use apps like dot control F.
Use apps. You should see this on this
view.
>> Control F.
>> Command F. Sorry.
>> As in like search.
>> Yeah, we're looking for literally the
UI. Okay. You don't have it.
Interesting.
>> Very interesting.
>> There's an apps preview.
>> No, it says it says confirm the button
reads use apps, not apps preview.
The app Okay. The app autod detects
whether your browser exposes the
experimental HTML and canvas APIs. When
they're not present, it shows use apps.
Maybe you needed to restart your Chrome
after you enabled that setting. Did you
do that?
>> I went here. I did this. Did canvas draw
element. This that's a different one.
Hold on.
>> Well, that would explain why we're
because because the app is basically not
presenting the option because we we
haven't enabled the right setting.
>> Hold on. We got this. We can figure this
out. We're smart. We have unlimited AI
enabled.
It says enabled.
>> Okay, just reboot Chrome.
>> I've rebooted Chrome like four times.
>> I mean, that's my typical advice as a
fellow developer. Reboot it again.
>> Always be rebooting.
Um, all right. Let's see.
>> Use Chrome Canary with the flag enabled.
Now once it Now I got to I have to
download yet another browser.
Currently 3D model displays.
Read the top of the screen where you see
the apps.
Okay, hold on chat. Pull up Chrome.
Um,
>> let's grab our URL, paste it in, copy,
paste.
>> So on on my side, where am I at? So,
the the GitHub app, I've just told it
that I want the theming to actually
reflect GitHub. Uh, so we're working on
that. That doesn't look like it's
working at all. Uh, I just saw that out
of the corner of my eye. Um,
>> uh, bro,
>> my my my co-pilot like building a
co-pilot agent control plane for this
thing has been cooking for 33 minutes
without my intervention. So,
>> what is it doing? Uh on my side or your
side?
>> On your side. This is I'm getting this
is what is this?
>> It went it got copilot SDK. It built a
UI around it. Uh I assume it's figured
out how to like get my co-pilot token
and uh and yeah, like we'll see if I can
actually kick off agents from that from
that thing.
>> And this is
>> Yeah, I don't get it. I don't understand
what we're supposed to be doing.
I don't understand the assignment. I can
change the background color.
Um, okay. We did this. Okay. Now, now
the apps screen is flickering pretty bad
in Chrome.
Send that off here.
>> So, are all of your sub agents done now
or you you just killed them?
>> I killed them. I mean, it did. It's
imple It says it's implemented all these
things. My guess is it's implemented
like
a minimal UI for all these things.
>> What's wrong?
>> Oh, sorry. More batteries for the mic.
Okay,
let's see here.
Yeah, my guess. Oh, I'll trace the
render timing and texture updates. The
app currently draws from both the
animation loop and the HTML and canvas
paint event.
So, it took a screenshot.
Oh, this is computer use.
>> Yeah, it's using Chrome. Okay.
Interesting. All right. Well, I'm just
going to let it
>> do it thing. You need the the battery
pack.
>> Yeah. On my side, uh you know, the
built-in uh shared browser over here, uh
and the agent is actually going through
and it's trying to validate. I was
trying to pull up the uh the signin uh
on YouTube, but apparently the way that
we've implemented this thing uh Google
thinks the browser is not secure. So I
need to we're working on a mitigation
technique. Um
so we will have to kick back to the real
browser for now. Uh but then I should be
able to get chat onto this thing. So
>> So what's wrong with yours?
>> So the the browser actually works. we're
using Chromium, but signing into apps,
it's like this is a malicious thing
because I guess I'm just running
Chromium with with, you know, nothing
else that doesn't recognize it. And so
it's getting flagged when I try to log
in. And so, um, basically like I wanted
to pull up the chat like someone in chat
said, but I can't do that because I
can't log in and you can't see the chat
unless you log in. And so now I'm going
to see like open in browser.
Okay. Yes. GitHub copot day.
>> Oh, dude, it's writing code. What? What
is it doing?
>> What's it doing? It's writing code in
the console
>> to test what's going on here. Very
interesting.
>> Um, what was I trying to do?
>> I mean, I do I hate to be hyperbolic,
but I do sometimes feel like this is
AGI. It's like I I'm not even doing
anything now.
It's just driving the browser.
>> Yep.
>> What am I supposed to do? Wait, this No,
this is the GitHub one. I wanted the
I don't want that. I want
What is my job exactly? Found it. Chrome
is using the fallback apps preview and
that dialog is stuck in a resize. Okay,
perfect. I'll stabilize it.
>> Okay. The only thing that, you know, the
agents do still kind of get tripped up
on is like if you're running multiple
things at once, like the ports and all
that, like it it does sometimes get
tripped up on that because when I open
in browser from my from my session here,
it actually opens it does open the
browser to the simulator, but it's the
running simulator from a different work
tree. So,
while I get the isolation of my code,
the processes do tend to get a little
garbled up sometimes. There's another
one I didn't enable. And whoever in the
chats was like, "Dude, read the top of
the
It says right here. It literally says
right here, make sure that you have
these two features enabled and then
restart Chrome." Okay, I think I've got
both of those.
>> We're developers, man. We don't read.
>> Yeah, we don't read.
>> I will never read your docs.
>> All right, we are listening to you.
We're doing the best we can.
Um,
hugging face attack in progress.
All right. Uh,
it's gonna work now. I'm I have medium
to low confidence. Here we go. Copy
link.
Gosh.
Still not working. It's supposed to be
here. Isn't it just supposed to be right
here?
is what's supposed to be where
>> the app where they supposed to show up.
>> It's not supposed to show apps preview.
Um
>> they should just be here on the phone.
>> Yes.
>> All right. So, I did did I do this one?
Draw element and
>> okay,
>> experimental web platform features. Let
me check this one. Yes, that's enabled.
The other one's enabled.
right here. This chit check. No, I don't
want to spell check that word.
Check this out.
Both of those these are both enabled
now.
Now what chat? Um,
actually it's not working in my It's
only Chrome Canary.
>> I made a joke at the top. I said, "The
hardest part's going to be getting this
thing enabled." And I wasn't kidding.
>> I was very serious when I said that.
>> I've downloaded two browsers in the last
25 minutes.
Can someone catch me up on what's going
on? No. No one knows. That's the
problem. We need to install other
browsers. All right, hold on.
>> So, yeah, if you're if you are just
jumping in, we have been given a task by
Wes. Um, he has this uh iPhone Duo
simulator thing he's built and he's
challenged us to populate this thing
with some apps. And so, Burke went and
asked uh asked GitHub Copilot app to go
in basically spin up 50 sub agents and
go do the thing. Um, I have a couple
things like the browser, a GitHub app,
and also like a a GitHub copilot app for
this Duo device that I'm working on. Um,
and right now I'm struggling with like
in general the interaction pattern of,
you know, this Chromium experience that
we have here. It's, as you can see, not
very buttery smooth. Um,
>> that's a hard problem to solve, though.
>> It is a very, very hard problem to
solve.
>> Just ask the AI what the layout should
be.
>> It's not even just the layout. It's like
I I mean I'm going to ask it about the
performance and say the performance is
not very good. You need to you need to
make the performance characteristics
better. But it's not even just that.
It's like
>> there's all kinds of weirdness going on
here with like accounts and things like
that. So I need to go back and
>> uh
No, not Edge Canary. Chrome Canary Wes.
There's like 30 browsers on my computer
now. a canary.
I can't I can't spell.
There we go. Stop. Oh my gosh.
All right, that's edge canary.
>> It's called check your Oh.
Um, so, um,
>> I don't have anything on my phone.
What's he talking about?
>> Check your Slack, man. Teams,
>> hold on. I'm going into
>> I'm going into Chrome Canary here.
Google Chrome Canary. Okay, here we go.
Get this working. Where are you at? What
are you doing? What are you doing?
>> Um, so I am We are here. Let me go full
screen here. Um, so I am I'm working on
a couple apps right now. So, where's
that apps preview thing? Um, apps
preview. GitHub. So, uh, we kind of have
a GitHub viewer here on, as you can see
here, we've reskinned this to basically
be similar to github.com in terms of its
theming. I got a little dark mode here.
Um, so I can come in here. I can browse
repositories. Let's see if I have any
fun one on Pierce Bogen and see if that
works. Pierce Bogen coloring book. I
like my coloring book app.
Click on that
and see I got all my issues here. So,
got some bugs I need to go address.
Looks like the markdown's not rendering
in the issue. So, let's let's have the
agent fix that. But, this is looking
pretty good. I got a an actual GitHub
app running on this Duo device right
here. Um, I can come in, I can browse
repos, I can look at all my issues. Do
we have any active pull requests? Yeah,
we got a couple active pull requests
here. You can see we have very
actionable ones like hi. Um and so uh
>> yeah the GitHub app is coming along. I
want to look at the let's see what other
things we had here. The browser one I
think is is giving me problem. I want to
look at this agent control plane. Oh
goodness it it looks like it this one's
starting to come together too. Um so we
have
let's see scrolling down.
Looks like we're trying to do some
things with, by the way, look. Mine is
rendering in the foldable thing. Look at
this in in the browser canvas.
See?
>> Well, how did you do that?
>> I I don't know what I did. It wasn't
working. It wasn't working in the other
one. Um, wait. Does something show in
the front?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. There we go.
>> What is going on? Why is this so hard
for me? Wait,
>> I I didn't do anything special. I don't
know why, but it's right. Okay. So
interesting. I don't know how I got
here. I got to be honest. Um but it
looks like it looks like I have some O
issues. So I'm getting tons of
connection checks.
>> Okay. I think I've got it.
>> Okay. All right. Let's jump back to you
then.
I'm rebooting Chrome.
>> What did you do? Were you did you go
enable other settings or did
>> No, it's just the same two settings but
this time on Chrome Canary.
>> Oh, you needed
>> They're working. Okay. All right. All
right. Okay. Oh my gosh.
>> All right. I'm excited about this.
>> I think there's too many apps on it,
though. Like it can't
>> Yeah. I can't even
>> Wait, does search work on the home
screen for apps to see like what there
is?
Uh, clips.
>> It does. That's super cool.
>> Wow, that's nice. Okay. Um, so if we do
books, there's a book. Can I turn the
phone around? Why does that keep
happening?
>> See, that's not happening for me. I
don't even have that setting enabled.
>> I just lost the whole phone.
>> It's no longer Duo. It's a What's What's
a single? I don't know what word I'm
looking for there. Oh, there we go. Oh,
there we go. Okay. So, like, how do I
Oh, here we go. Okay.
>> Oh,
>> can I close it? How do you close it? You
do not close it.
>> Yeah, it cannot be closed. But wait, I
feel like your apps are taking
advantage.
>> Boom.
>> They're not taking advantage of that
real estate, though.
>> What do you mean? Yeah, they are.
>> Oh, is is that like the equivalent of
your lock screen in this new UX paradigm
when you have it closed? Like, shouldn't
if you have what is it? What app is this
library? Should the library be also able
to access the front? Because there's
actually three,
>> but it's not right now.
>> No. Okay. So, we need to what? Tell it
that all these apps need to be able to
>> Yeah, I guess so. Ed turn spin around.
Okay. All right. So, we just need to let
it know like Okay. Okay. I got it. I'm
on it.
Okay. Just say okay. Okay. All of these
apps need to work in
book. What are the different the modes
are? Book, closed, book, and flat.
Closed.
Book flat and flat. Intent modes.
Um
you're gonna have to figure out
>> and so you were in the the main session
the UI for each of these
um form factors. Okay. Yes, I'm in the
main I'm in this main one which was
controlling all of these.
>> So then it's going to cascade this
message to
>> I assume it's just going to like go back
to each one of these and start sending
messages out again. We'll see. But I
feel like some of the apps did have the
front screen working. I might be
misremembering. But
>> is this a graph?
>> Am I doing a graph right now? Is this a
graph chat?
>> Um,
yeah. Loops and graphs. If you aren't
doing loops and graphs, what are you
doing? Are you even doing engineering in
2026? Um,
>> so
>> yeah, the goal is to watch them code
crazy shenanigans using the power of
GitHub code. You're exactly right.
>> That that is exactly the goal. when we
ideulated this session.
>> Yep. Trying to get the simulator to
work. Yes. And we did. Success.
Yeah. I'll make the share I'll make the
shared app shell adapt to the phone's
posture so all the apps keep their state
when you fold it. I'm checking the cover
display and tent orientation first.
Those need usable single screen
navigation, not just a scaled down
two-creen layout. Got it.
Yeah, man. I was thinking like you do
realize chat that a year ago at this
time we did not have Opus 45.
>> I know it.
>> What did we have? Was it Sonnet 35? Is
that what everyone was doing?
>> No, we were we were further along. It
might be Sonnet 4 around this time. No,
because Opus Opus the Opus thing was
like December, right? Uh
>> but wait a minute. Opus was Opus was
around before 45,
>> but it wasn't like Opus as people
>> know it today know it today,
>> right? It was like well this was in the
time when it was like well we have these
like we have reasoning models.
>> Yeah.
>> And then we have coding models and it
wasn't it wasn't sure like well should I
use 01 to code or should I use opus to
code or no is that a misuse of that
model and now it's like every model is a
coding model first and foremost.
>> Yes.
>> Well because every task is a coding
task. Like if you are analyzing data
sure you can do that in Excel but you
can also use Python right. Um, so like
you know it turns out making every task
workable with coding is actually very
important for if you're trying to
achieve AGI because with coding you can
literally create anything as we're
seeing today. But yeah, I mean you're
right like um so we track this metric at
at GitHub called uh like retained code
from agent and it's essentially one way
that we are able to say like how good is
it is our agent with a particular model
and with I think GBD41 right when agent
mode and VS code shipped we were at like
50 52% retain code from agent which by
the way is is super cool like it was 0%
before yeah like you literally were
using natural language and you were
getting 50% of the code kept Right. And
now with these with the the latest
models and the GitHub copilot harness,
we are seeing like upwards of 90 and
above percent retain code from agent.
And so that does drastically change how
you partner with this thing. Like I
remember the first time we started doing
live streams.
Our trust in the models wasn't quite
there. We were supervising every single
tool command. We're watching the agent
intently like synchronously every single
one. So as the models got better, what
makes it what becomes possible? Okay,
now I can run three of these because I
don't need to closely supervise each
individual one, right? And so like our
partnership has changed as the models
got better. And that was just one year
ago. And so it does make you wonder like
I mean let alone one year like where are
we going to be in a month or two or
three, right? Um so things things are
definitely changing very fast. Um that's
for sure. But it's super fun. Like you
can have like a very like scared mindset
about that of like change is hard and
like I'm I'm nervous. But like I
actually find it very exhilarating that
like we're able to go and build things
like this and we can literally ideate
software into existence like at the tips
of our fingertips or voice.
>> But then the question becomes and I'm
curious. I'm going to ask Chad about
this because one of the things that
Chad's complaining about is that we're
using these huge expensive models
because we have unlimited tokens and and
they do not. Right. And that's a valid
complaint. But
>> certainly in the future, we will arrive
at a place and point in time when
everyone has basically unmetered access
to this level of intelligence. There's
no doubt. Right. Well, and and like you
see that the you know the next
generation of models like sure there's
always going to be the frontier ones but
like very quickly like the you know fast
capable cheaper models do have the same
capability as like the powerful models
of a generation ago.
>> Exactly. And so like this sort of
intelligence will roll down into the
next like you know flash equivalent at
some point in time here that will be
distilled and then the cost point for
these sorts of things will be much more
accessible I think like also in real
life right like
not every task I'm going to just put the
most expensive bottle on right um I'm
going to be a little bit more discerning
I'm going to use things like auto I'm
going to use hydrofusion right um but
like for for the purposes this fun demo,
it makes sense to
>> Yeah. Because we only have a certain
amount of time. Yeah. Exactly.
>> But I I I think I the reason why I bring
that up is because if you think if you
like someone once told me when you
listen to someone from a big model lab
talk about something, they're talking
about something that you're going to see
6 to 12 months down the road, right? So
what they're working with today is what
you will be working with in 12 months.
And I think in some sense like what you
see us doing here today, you will
probably have access to in some form or
fashion in 12 months, right? You'll have
that level of intelligence at a at a c
this is not a promise, but just
generally how I see this shake out. So
then the question becomes
what are we do like where does this go
as developers? Like there's this big
debate about do we read the code? Should
we be reading the code? Like what's the
right way to work? What are the
workflows? What are the skills we need?
And as these models get smarter and
smarter, what I find is you don't need
that stuff. You don't need
all of the workflows that we've
assembled to try to make the AI do
things correctly. You don't need
anymore. And then it just leaves me
wondering
like what are what are we going to be
doing 12 months from now then? Like is
it ju is it literally just asking the
agent for things? Is it just walking up
to the Star Trek food replicator and
punching in what you want and getting a
cheeseburger and that's it? And then
we're just going to be walking around
being like, "Hey, I asked the agent for
such and such. Let me show you what the
agent did."
>> I actually think the the challenge that
I see in practice for a lot of teams
living at the the frontier of AI, even
who have un say you have unlimited
access, you can run fable everything.
the the challenges that those teams
struggle with is not building the thing,
it's everything else. Right? So
>> such as
>> um when you have so much throughput in
your codebase, even with a very capable
model, you will regress things. There
will be weird architectural drift that
happens over time. um the uh like you
will have increasingly problems
prioritizing the right like you don't
just want your product to become you
know a ton of random knobs and you are
always encouraged not to do that because
it costs real time to do and with the
cost of these things taking less time
now you have to be more discerning about
what you do so every a lot of teams I
talked to and I I gave a talk on the v
code team's approach at build about this
of like hey we're seeing our issue count
skyrocket we're seeing our open PRs,
even with things like agent merge and
the GitHub compod app skyrocket. Um, you
start to ask like how are you making
sure that like the product is not
drifting away from what we actually want
it to be. And so in a weird way like I
actually am like one of the reasons I'm
very optimistic about GitHub copilot
besides I think we have an awesome
harness, we have a great product, we
have access to all the models is I
really do actually think like a lot of
this is going to come back to how good
is your engineering system because sure
you can sling code but you really we're
ship we're shipping real things right
that have to be production grade and as
you have all this velocity like typical
engineering systems are bad to begin
with and they were not made for this
level of throughput right and so I
actually think like we'll spend a lot
more time on engineering systems type of
problems than we do today,
>> right? But it's not going to be
reviewing code because I see today this
whole like well you know you should be
the one looking at the code before it
gets merged and then that's your code,
right? You're your thing is making sure
that agents are writing quality code.
But the problem is then you've just
shifted the bottleneck down the road.
You're not really moving any faster than
you were before if you're actually
reviewing code.
>> I think that is an unrealistic
perspective like um it will be a
temptation in every single team and
every single organization to say this AI
is very powerful you can do more right
so then you'll do more and I think it's
very easy to say like well you should
have responsibility for reviewing every
single line of code in practice that
will not happen right people are not
going to do that um and so then if
that's what the human inertia is of like
okay we're not going to look at this
thing anymore it's some sort of artifact
which by the way I think is how
programming has always worked we've up
continuously upleveled right like I'm
not in assembly instructions anymore and
then we got like somewhat more modern
programming languages and somewhat more
modern programming languages and maybe
this is just the next abstraction. So
it's it's it's not uncommon, but like if
you're like, I'm I have to review every
line of code, if you're being asked to
deliver like at a much faster pace,
that's just not practical, right?
>> You will be the bottleneck for your
team's ability to move forward.
>> And if you're not writing the code, I do
think there is like a
>> it is cognitively more difficult to jump
into a PR and understand someone else's
architecture than it is if you like when
you artically crafted that code, right?
Oh, it's the worst. And so like I don't
even actually know that you will be a
good reviewer of your own code because
you don't write it in the way you used
to before.
>> You didn't write it at all.
>> Right.
>> Yes. And and then nobody's emotionally
invested in it. So like you don't really
care if the PR gets merged or not. Do
you know what I mean? There's a human
element here. Anyway, there's a very
human element. Somebody had said they
said we will reach a saturation point.
Maybe like Olympic level sprinters being
able to improve their times rapidly
until 10 seconds for 100 meters. So this
would be like Moore's law. talking about
a Moor's law in ter but what are we
talking about here some are you saying
that like in terms of cost or
performance like I keep thinking these
models what'd you get
>> I just got the GitHub copilot app
working in this duo so this is real
GitHub copilot SDK I I just said hello
right let's do another one hello chat um
default model I'm a little nervous to
open the model picker sometimes I'm
flyed things that I should not too. Um,
and okay, I got agent is running and I
got back a response. Um, and so, uh,
yeah, like this is actually I got a diff
viewer here. Like I can actually go and
build a simple HTML page to promote the
live stream with Burke and Pierce at
GitHub copilot day. So, this is actually
using real copilot SDK, my real GitHub
copilot subscription. Oh, I need to add
YOLO mode to this. Look, I have to do
tool approvals. Um, so I'm going to
allow once.
>> Oh, it's the tool approvals are coming
through, too. Wait, so the SDK is
pushing all that.
>> Yeah, the this is the SDK running in the
simulator of the Duo and it looks like
um Okay, so now like we have let's see,
am I getting changes coming in? No, it
hasn't created the page yet. Um, so
we're going to see if we get changes.
And then to get extremely meta, we
already have a browser. I need a browser
preview in my Duo simulator browser um
to actually render this website. Um
okay, so it render it created. Look, I
mean it's not the prettiest thing, but
we got we got a diff viewer here. It's
actually showing the thing. Um
how can I open this in the browser?
What's the path? That is super cool. So,
we added we got a browser, we got a real
GitHub app, we got a real GitHub
co-pilot app for the Duo.
>> Yes, we have a camera, we have we
actually have all these apps, but a lot
of them don't work. So, like uh like
let's look at weather. What kind of
weather app do we get here? Like I don't
think it's 18 degrees in San Francisco.
I'm going to go out on a limb. Um
maybe it is.
Maybe if that's cells,
it's got to be cyn
>> freedom freedom units or not.
>> Yeah, I don't know. Uh, okay. So, we
have but we have all these different
apps here, but I think a lot of them
just probably just don't work.
>> I would expect that that would be the
case. What would the app store? Did we
ever try that one and even see
>> the app store
>> because it said a built-in app store?
>> Yeah. Um, let's put it flat so we can
actually like
>> paper orbit.
>> All right. Is this just like mock data?
What happens if you try to install this?
>> Add to simulated library.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Now go back. What was that?
>> Is it actually there? Uh, paper orbit.
>> All right. Search.
>> I'm assuming it's not.
>> Whoa. Whoa. Orbit.
>> Nope.
>> Yeah, cuz it doesn't actually exist.
>> I mean, I assumed that that was the
case.
>> You know what would be really cool
though is if we had an app store where
it imagines apps and then when I install
one, then just like create it on the
fly.
>> Yeah, let's do that. I like that idea.
on demand app store creation. Type your
idea and we build it on.
>> I gota tell it to stop what you're
doing. Okay, stop what you're doing. Um,
okay. Bit of a pivot here. Instead of
having all these other apps, let's have
an app store and I want you to just
imagine a ton of different apps that can
be in that app store. You don't actually
have to create them, just imagine them.
And then when I click on one to install
it, I want you to show an installing
uh animation. But then while you're
installing the app is being installed, I
need it to I need you to build it and
then actually add it to the simulator.
Okay. Now, what's what's interesting
here, Pierce, is that because
because the canvas
is not showing doesn't have the 3D
acceleration, I'm having to do it in the
browser. How is the agent going to talk
to this browser? Exactly. It's probably
going to do computer use. If it was in
the app, it could just talk to it
directly.
>> Playright. Potentially
>> could use playright. Okay, we'll just
again this is one of those things where
you would before you would have to say
how many lines of code have we written?
>> 20,000. Y'all want to see how many how
many AI credits do you think we've used
here?
>> I have no idea.
>> Do y'all want to see?
>> Chad, you want to see how many how many
AI credits?
>> I've written a lot of code over here,
too.
>> Hold on. I'm going to go down. Oh, wait.
Use my local copilot CLI. using API
local co-pilot CLI. Yeah.
>> 2,642
AI credits. So $2642.
>> That's not bad.
>> No.
>> For what we cooked up here.
>> Come on.
>> And this was all Astra, right?
>> This is all Astra.
>> Astra on medium.
>> Yep.
>> I do I do feel like there's also this
temptation from people of like I need to
always be running high, extra high, max
reasoning, and I just really don't think
that that's necessary. And also it it
adds so much like time to the trajectory
that it makes the interaction speed so
much slower. Generally
>> I think that if anything beyond as I
understand it for most of these models
once you move beyond high there's
diminishing return. So you're getting a
little bit more performance but at a lot
more cost
>> extremely more cost and in the case of I
mean admittedly offline evaluations are
not representative of the full story and
that's why we have online data too but
like we saw with some models in VS Code
the higher reasoning efforts actually
degraded benchmark performance it wasn't
that they stayed the same and cost more
it actually like our performance went
down which was interesting
>> interest yeah so like just because the
so a higher reasoning level doesn't It's
not smarter. That just means what then?
>> It's just spending. So basically before
it responds, it's introspecting and
saying what do I need to do? And it's
generating more chain of thought
essentially which in theory that chain
of thought helps to guide the agent when
it does its next turn because it has
more instructions on what tool to call
as part of the agent loop, right? And so
in theory by frontloading more thinking,
right, the agent reasons more about what
actually needs to be done. it's more
efficient the rest of the trajectory and
does the right tools, right, everything.
It doesn't like prod around quite as
much. In reality, that isn't always
actually the case. Sometimes it it tries
to be too smart for its own good.
>> So then
so then it could if it's reasoning more
then it could if it thinks longer, it
could think to a better answer or it
could overthink.
>> Yes. Just like a person,
>> right?
Like you can over like you can big brain
a solution as an engineer and it may
just be like hey you should have just
picked something way simpler. You way
overthought that right.
>> Yeah. Oh that happens to me all the
time. It was like this is I'm way over
complicating this.
>> Exactly. Um
yeah I am I am trying to uh
I'm trying to figure out what I should
do next on this on this Duo simulator I
got rocking over here. Um because we got
we got agents actually going right. So,
I'm trying to figure out like what I
should do next.
>> You should definitely build it from the
co-pilot app on the simulator. Let's see
what chat says. I used $30 to build the
phone UI last night. Yeah. So, $30,
$20,000.
$30. $26. It's not that expensive. But,
you know, if you're doing this all,
we've been here for an hour. So, $25 in
an hour.
>> Imagine you just did that all day. Fair.
And we're only r Well, I did fan out to
a bunch of agents, but you could spend
what a couple hundred bucks a day, $200
a day, five days a week. It's going to
add up.
>> True. But but also like how if you had
if I had given you this as a real
engineering task, how much time would
you have spent on it?
>> No, I would not. This would have t Well,
yes, but like say this was not a
contrived experience like doing
something like this would have taken you
like a month probably or a couple weeks
at least. though, and it just works.
>> I mean, that is very true. Um, but
>> there's a there is a trade-off. Your
time also has value, right?
>> Like, you would never do this with your
own money, right? You wouldn't go in
here and build an iPhone.
>> Of course not. You're not you're not
toying around like that. But like I'll
give an example like the GitHub copilot
app, right? That came into existence
over the course of literally a couple
months from a team of like five people,
five to seven people.
>> And uh like that would have never been
possible. Like I remember okay we had VS
code we had agent mode okay now we need
copilot CLI that took a couple months
right um okay now we need to do app like
that's even more condensed and like so
like I think like things like that that
would have been like oh you know at
Microsoft or any big company we need to
go hire a team and boot this team and
hire and we need to write 15 docs on
what this thing's going to be and that's
going to take six months and before
anyone writes a line of code okay
finally we have people hired now we need
to go do that like that app in like old
Microsoft time would have taken us like
two years to ship.
>> Yeah.
>> And we got it to market in like a month
and a half, two months.
>> So like,
>> but now it does feel like though that
now that we're moving so much quicker
>> that there's more features than anyone
can even keep up with, right? Like you
can't you can't keep up with the out
even as someone who's just getting
>> the final output, you can't even keep up
with the output. So we're saying like
you can't keep up with PRs, just focus
on the output.
>> But it looks like you're not going to be
able to keep up with the output either.
So, but that's why that's why I actually
think one of the big challenges and we I
again not to plug my talking but we
talked about I talked about this with
Josh at build is like
>> one of the challenges often for many
teams now the temptation will be to do
everything. It's actually saying no is
like what you need to do more of as a
team because yeah like if you just add a
million knobs to your product like that
is not going to result in a good
product. Yeah,
>> sure your agent could do 50 sub aents
and add all these things but like is
that actually a good idea right? So like
as engineers you have to do like a lot
more product thinking right because your
your job will be increasingly to say no
because the temptation will just be to
do more.
>> Well and part of the problem is I think
with these agents if the agent is
working then you're like okay I'm going
to go do something else while this agent
I'm going to do a second thing. I'm
going to do a third thing. Yep.
>> And I don't know if you saw um Gwen had
posted on Ax and she said, "Why don't
you read While the Agent Works?" And she
had like a book out and I I had this
epiphany when I read that that like,
"Oh,
>> you don't need to just keep working just
because the agent's working." You don't
need to do that. I think as humans,
we're kind of wired to like, well, I'm
supposed to be working. I need to do
something else. But then we're just like
flinging slop everywhere. There's too
many things going on. You can't keep up.
So yeah, read read while the agent
>> speaking of reading, I'm going back
through the comments. I got a question.
Can you work in the same repo you're
running the app in? Yes, we have
isolation. So each of these um each of
these agents is running in their own
work tree and when they're running
something like npm rumdev, if the port
is taken by another agent, it will just
use a new port. So you can run multiple
processes from multiple agents at the
same time.
>> It's a Canadian app, Wes is saying in
the chat. So, it was Canadian units,
>> not freedom units.
>> It's a Canadian app.
>> Um, so there's that. Um,
>> well, we need to fix that.
>> Yes,
>> this is the worst bug. We have moved.
>> Got to get back into Fahrenheit ASAP.
>> Um,
>> trying to see where we are here. We're
not quite to our dynamic app store
that's just going to like let us imagine
apps on the fly,
>> but we're close.
>> We're We are close. I I'm actually like
we've been doing this what, like an hour
and a hour, hour and a halfish, and like
we we actually like I was a little
nervous because it took us a while to
get Canary Chrome installed. But like I
feel like, you know, we've made a lot of
progress here.
>> We did. Yeah, we got so we got past the
browser issue, which I feel like I
should have just gone into the chat and
been like, "Hey, use the agent browser
to get the right browser and get this
whole thing working." Like, why did I
spend any time doing that at all?
>> I think about that all the time. I spend
like an hour doing something. Why did I
just waste an hour doing that? I should
have just like deferred that.
>> I don't know. But I do it all the time.
I had I did this the other day where So,
this machine right here, I was wiped and
set up new before coming out here. And
when I was setting it up, I I tried to
run npm install and it's like, well, you
know, node's not installed. I was like,
oh crap, I gotta set all this stuff up.
And I was like, wait a minute, why don't
I just ask Copilot to set it all up? So,
I just said, what is missing from this
machine? It's like, I don't know, you
probably need uh homebrew, rip grab, and
pnpm, uv, go, rust, open JDK, docker
desktop, docker cli, and I was like,
okay, install all of it.
>> And it just went and did it. It
installed homebrew first and like just
set up the whole machine. It's like as a
developer, as a human, I have to just
think every single time I do something.
Should I just have asked AI to do this?
>> Maybe.
>> I don't know. Answer's probably yes.
>> So, question from Martin here in the
chat. Thanks for hanging out with us,
Martin. Uh, when do I create nested
sessions in the app? So, I can give my
answer. Maybe you have your own. So,
nested sessions. Do you mind going back
to the thing and showing like okay so
this is a nested session right we have
we have a parent session and we have
child sessions so there's two scenarios
where I primarily use this in the app
>> one is like uh when I have like a
particular task and I very clearly have
clean separation of work that I want to
set set this up into different threads
that I can follow yes you can do this
with sub aents that are not nested
sessions but the I I just feel like from
a UX perspective the visibility isn't as
good with sub aents sometimes and these
are pretty clean separation like each
thread is an app, right? So that's one
scenario. The other one is like I use
this pattern in the app all the time. I
call it like the chief of staff pattern
where I like will have one session where
I'm basically commanding the work. So
like I will very frequently say like
what are the top five century you know
uh bugs that we have right in the last
seven days in the GitHub copod app and
like it'll come back and it'll say these
are the five and like rather than me
going copy paste I'm going to go you
know create five sessions I just like
create the five sessions right
>> and so like in that case they are
isolated right and so yes there's the
isolation thing like in the first
scenario but it's also that I am able to
mentally not have to go and manage those
five I just say keep me updated ated on
progress in the main thread and it it
really is like a chief of staff. You're
like if anything comes up like let me
know basically otherwise I trust you to
do your thing. And so then rather than
me managing five chats I'm managing one
chat and so that's kind of my
partnership model because when you
really start leaning into this
parallelization thing your brain is not
made to handle like 50 things at once,
right? And so you kind of have to come
up with these like constructs like this
nested sessions thing to actually and
the chief of staff model to actually be
able to achieve that. The other one is
like canvas. Have you been have you been
using canvases at all in the GitHub
copilot app?
>> Oh yeah.
>> Yeah. So like the other like what if
there was just a visual representation
of what you're trying to do? And so I
think when people hear canvas they're
like just okay there's an HTML file in
the side, right? But like a canvas in
GitHub copilot app land is something
that can actually reach back into the
app and control it. So like we have a
century canvas going back to the century
example.
>> I boot that thing up in standup full
screen that puppy. Okay, these are the
top five century issues. rather than me
just copy pasting that right that
context back into the app I can just say
all right
>> create session create session create
session create session right and then I
just stay in that canvas and it'll
report back to me and so it's like yet
another way you can kind of uplevel your
partnership as you parallelize yourself
more that's such a hard word parallelize
>> parallelize I know it
>> I I've gotten better at it because I you
know it's part of the talk track on the
app but it is a hard word to say
>> I think so I think of it the same way
but it's like um it's almost like with
working with people so if you hire one
person then you work with that person.
If you hire two people, then you're
working with two people and you're
interfacing with those people. Yep. And
this this works well. But at some point,
if you have 20 people working for you,
you have a real problem. All you do is
meet with people. And so for me, once it
gets past like two or three agents, I'm
now delegating. I need an agent to
manage the other agents. I don't want to
talk to those agents.
>> I need someone to manage that. So that
paradigm for me is extremely helpful.
So, like here's an example of like an an
iPhone app that I've been working on
where there's a bunch of different
issues and I had one sub agent fan out,
>> decide which ones to turn into PRs, turn
them into PRs, test them, then come back
and tell me, you know,
>> all the tests are passed, are we good to
go? Does everything look good? So then I
can go in. I don't want to know anything
about these other agents. So that's I
guess that's how I would think about it.
All right. Where where where are we?
Run assistance
still loading. I'll run a real install
to confirm the generation. I can't wait.
Let's just No, still not. Still broken.
We're in a broken state.
All right, chat.
>> So, while you do that, another question
in the chat. By uh so that's supported
in VS Code, Copilot app, uh Copilot CLI,
uh all the major copilot clients support
BY. Now the comment was specifically
about bring your own key for code
completions though and uh the
interesting thing about that is we
actually did very deeply explore that
scenario um when we were getting a lot
of feedback about completions and our
completions model and the interesting
thing is like if you go look not just in
GitHub copilot but any of the major
providers in this space their code
completion models are all custom models
and there's a reason for that like most
of these models are very bad at what's
called fill-in-the-middle where you have
like a code snippet and a code snippet
and I need you to insert something in
the middle. And so there is a reason
that all of these providers have gone
and built their own models, us included,
for things like code completion and
nextedit suggestions because most of the
off-the-shelf models, even if you put
Astra on it, which it would be super
slow, but it would it would probably
actually not do as good a job as you
think on that sort of task. Um, and so
like purpose-built models really work
for it. And so while we could add bring
your own key for code completions, we
just found that when we actually tried
this with like some off-the-shelf
models, it did not actually work. And so
that's why it hasn't been prioritized as
part of our roadmap.
>> Interesting. I did not know that. I So
they're better at completing than they
are finding out what's in the middle.
>> They're better at generating new things,
right, than dealing with the messiness
of a very limited context of your code
and a couple lines above and a couple
lines below, right?
>> All right. So what are you what are you
showing here?
>> Um, so this is our app. So now we just
have an app store. That's it.
Installed. Discover all categories. Oh,
wait. Here's a scroll bar. Shelf light.
Shape path. Loop studio. Build a rhythm
of your own. Word window. One new word.
A wider world. What are these? Pocket
tides. A puzzle with room to breathe.
Okay.
>> Okay. So, when when we actually click
install on this, allegedly what will
happen is this app is going to be built
for us on the fly.
>> Allegedly.
>> Okay.
>> Install.
>> All right. The app builder requires npm
rundev. Static previews cannot build
apps.
>> What?
>> Well, it's not. In all fairness, it's
not done.
>> It's still running.
>> We're we're we're coming in.
>> I'm jumping in. Yeah. I can't wait. I
need it right now.
>> I need it right now.
>> I can't wait.
>> So, I I also see a couple other things
in this app. There's automations. Do you
have any automations configured?
>> Um,
>> are you pretty light on the auto?
because I wiped this one. But one of the
ones I have um is this one is one called
dead code removal
>> that I use. And this one runs every
single day and it just goes across my
repos and it just removes dead code.
Remove dead code and submit a
PR. But then this right here is a
problem because if you tell an an LLM to
remove dead code,
>> it's going to find dead code every
single time and it eventually will just
start removing types,
>> right? Which you don't want. So what I
do is say remove dead code and then chat
I say
and then check with um uh you know opus
and see whether or not the code needed
to be removed
or are if you are inventing work. Now
the reason why this works is because the
first model's job is to find dead code.
It's going to find it every time. The
second model's job is just to determine
whether or not that is invented work or
actually valuable and then say um do
whatever Opus decides, right? Something
like this and then
>> this and this runs every day like 9:00
a.m. just across my repos just removing
dead code. So it's just an example. It's
a very simple example of an automation
that you can use. Uh and this would be
considered a loop.
>> Yeah, I I have I I like that example. I
have like some like non-engineering
ones that I have like you know help me
prepare for my day. So it goes through
work IQ all my meetings pull stuff
context from Slack uh you know teams
etc. I have one unfortunately for
message triage on Slack and Teams
because I wake up I have hundreds of
unread DMs and it's like just even you
know doing the cursory clickthrough is
going to take too long and so I have
like a prompt built up of like if Martin
or Burke you know is messaging me we
should really prioritize like surfacing
that these other people maybe not. No,
I'm just kidding. Um and then uh like a
ton for like telemetry for feedback
triage on the GitHub copilot app. We
have like a massive uh channel with like
thousands of people internally at GitHub
where people just come in and give
feedback about the app. I did have an
automation that was basically going
through there. It would like investigate
their issues. It would tell me if any of
them are real. Um it would propose fixes
if they're relatively self-contained.
But now like actually for that flow, I'm
using the new Slack integration. Um, and
I'm just like saying like, you know,
anytime anyone is posting in this
internal channel like at GitHub, like go
go investigate this because people post
like a screenshot, a video, their logs,
right? Oh, yeah.
>> And like rather than me like
downloading, copy pasting it over into
the app, whatever, right? Even having an
agent go do that. I'm just like, oh, at
GitHub, like figure it out.
>> Yeah. It's become it's too much to keep
up with. Like you just can't, right? And
even sometimes I'll like I'll have
feedback and I'm like, where do I go?
and you're like this Slack channel and I
go in there and there's like
>> I don't know, man. There's like 600
>> uh posts from the last hour
like you could spend all of your time
just responding to that and get no work
done, right? And so like that is what I
mean when I say the challenge for a lot
of teams is managing that like that is a
different level of throughput than
you've ever had to deal with in terms of
feedback and changes.
>> Okay, so we have this it looks like this
is actually working. It says your app is
the local build. So, it's building the
app and then hopefully it will install
it here. But
>> I'm so excited for the payoff here. I
hope we can get there.
>> I mean, do you think we get to a world
chat where like this is the world we
live in where like you're on your phone,
you're like, man, I'd really like to
have an app that does this and you go to
the and you just say that and then it
just appears a few minutes later. I
mean, why not? Why can't
>> I don't I don't actually think so. Not
because the agent is Well, because
>> I two years ago, everyone was like, "Oh,
all these SAS companies are dead. said
anyone can replicate their software in 5
minutes. And that's true for the
extremely base case of the software. But
like then there's all this software that
has endured for decades. And I'm not
entirely convinced that just because you
can vibe code something that kind of
looks like the same thing that it's
going to replace it. It turns out if
you're doing like,
>> you know, payments or you're you're
doing things like that. You you do not
want something that's just like, you
know, some something that someone pulled
together that no one owns, right? And so
while possible, I actually just from
human nature perspective, I'm not
confident that that will be the future.
But it's cool that that's like even
something you can discuss as Oh, look at
that. Front screen.
>> There it is.
>> However, however I'm supposed to
reference this
>> building. I don't even know if this is
actually building. Uh I think it's front
screen.
>> I mean, it shouldn't take this long
unless we were installing some
ridiculous npm packages.
>> I mean, it still isn't done. It's It's
still cooking over here. It's still
cooking. It's testing.
>> I love these new models like Astra and
the others. They just test. They don't
need to You don't need to tell them
there's a canvas. You don't need to tell
them to run test. They just figure it
out on their own. All right, we're
coming down to the last few minutes
here. What What do we need to What do
people need to take away from GitHub
copilot day?
>> Oh man, there's there's so many cool
things. Like I I think like our
intention with this event is like to
your point like things are changing so
fast, right? And there's always new
things introduced. And so we just wanted
to have a moment of reflection of like
how has you know how we work changed
with the latest things in the GitHub
copod space and what are some of the
most notable things and so you know we
talked about the new GitHub copilot app
right we've we've demoed that
extensively in this session. You can get
that from gh.app
give that a try. Um it's been super
awesome to see like how people are
adopting that and using it not just for
engineering tasks but like all work. Um,
and then uh also like new interaction
patterns like the Slack stuff Megan
showed off. I referenced the scenario of
how we're going into Slack at GitHub,
you know, fix this bug. Going where your
context already is, having people who
are reporting the bug actually join in
and building the solution with you.
That's super cool. Um, we talked about
some of our model and harness
improvement work like hydrofusion. Um
Patrick came and talked about uh kind of
how our stack is evolving with agent
host protocol to be not just you know
capable of running on your local machine
but any arbitrary remote and so you know
keep an eye on announcements between now
and universe we'll keep making this like
remote agent story more of a thing on
your own compute and so just a couple of
the things like there's always so many
things to keep up with in our world but
we just wanted to share like a a couple
new things that we have been working on
that have changed how we're working here
at GitHub and we're excited for you to
give it a try. Yeah, I totally agree.
And I think that, you know, for me, what
I noticed is a lot of people, Mino,
because GitHub Copilot has been around
for so long. It was the original. Yes.
>> And uh and we're still going and so much
has changed that even for me watching
the keynote, I was like, whoa, I didn't
realize it was a mobile canvas. I had no
idea. Uh and so and and then knowing
about the GitHub Copilot app and people
ask me all the time, you know, they're
like, I'm using Visual Studio Code or
I'm using this or that, you know, what
is this? Yep. And hopefully people have
seen, you know, and you got a good um
you got a good feel for what the GitHub
Copilot app is,
>> what it can do. And um yeah, I think
it's super exciting to see things like
hydroofusion and to hear words like 60%
cheaper. I think everybody wants to hear
that right now. I want even I want to
hear that.
>> Yep.
>> Um
>> go ahead and continue here. But yeah, it
it's been
first of all, thank everybody for
joining us. You know, we're so thank you
so much for being here with us. But
also, it's been it's just been a wild
ride to get to this point and we have
even bigger announcements coming at
Universe, which is in is it in it's just
in about a month, right? So,
>> like if you enjoyed this and you're
like, "Wow, I didn't know all this stuff
was there." Uh you haven't seen anything
yet. Oh, there's a lot there's a lot
more to come.
>> So, yeah, we'll leave you with that. Um,
thank you so much for being with us.
That's a wrap on the first ever GitHub
copilot day. And if you were here,
>> you are a founder by definition for the
event.
>> We love it. Yeah. Like we we we
seriously love the the community we have
around GitHub, GitHub Copilot, VS Code.
Like it's it's been awesome to see like
how over the past couple years you've
shaped what these products have become.
And so, thanks for joining us today,
learning what's new, seeing all the cool
stuff, and we're super excited to party
with you guys at Universe in a month.
>> Oh, no. I think they're going to throw.
>> Oh, we got something happening here.
It's going to happen.
>> We're going to end it.
>> It would not be a an event like this
unless we had a special surprise.
Tada.
>> One's in my soda.
>> Oh, no. Thanks for joining everybody. We
really appreciate it. Bye.
>> Signing off.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.